<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Title</title></titleStmt><publicationStmt><p>Publication Information</p></publicationStmt><sourceDesc><p>Information about the source</p></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text><body><pb n="372"/><div type="entry"><head xml:id="technology"> 		technology, modern 	</head><div type="article"><p><name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> developed an advanced modem technology in the three decades 
                        following <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/World_War_II">World War II</name>; although most of this technology 
                        was initially imported from abroad, <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> had in certain areas 
                        surpassed the technological level of the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">United States</name> and 
                        other advanced nations by the late 1970s. 		</p><p><hi rend="bold">Historical Development</hi>---Starting industrialization much later than most Western nations, Japan had to invest 
                        time and capital in laying the industrial, economic, and educational foundations for a technology that was already in practical 
                        use abroad. From the very beginning of the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Meiji_period">Meiji period</name> 
                        (1868-1912) the national government promoted the development of industry and technology in
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> as part of its conscious policy of modernizing and militarily 
                        strengthening the nation. This policy was given particular emphasis by the 
                        <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/First_Sino-Japanese_War">Sino-Japanese War</name> of 1894-95, and the 
                        <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Russo-Japanese_War">Russo-Japanese War</name> of 1904-05, and there was a systematic 
                        buildup of industry and technology following <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/World_War_I">World War 1</name>. The 
                        Production Research Council, which was established in 1910 and reorganized as the Temporary Industrial Council in 1927 assisted 
                        certain designated industries. The INSTITUTE OF PHYSICAL AND CHEMICAL RESEARCH was organized in 1917 under the joint sponsorship of 
                        government and industry for the purpose of developing and applying creative technology. During the 1930s there was a rapid development 
                        of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan's</name> heavy and chemical industries. In this decade all industry and 
                        technology was mobilized for war (the <name type="event" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Mukden_Incident">Manchurian Incident of 1931</name>,
                        Japan's invasion of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Republic_of_China">China</name> in 1937, and its entry into 
                        <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/World_War_II">World War II</name> in 1941), and new developments were limited to 
                        military technology. Advances were made in shipbuilding, optics, and aircraft; however, because of the narrow application to military 
                        technology, <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan's</name> overall productivity remained far below that of the 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">United States</name>. </p><p> Although most of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan's</name> technology was imported (of some 400 important 
                        discoveries and inventions in industrial technology from 1868 through the mid-1960s, only 70 were originally developed and produced in 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name>), the following are some of the inventions made by the 
                        <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japanese_people">Japanese</name> in the period before 
                        <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/World_War_II">World War II</name>: the production of 
                        <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Takadiastase">Taka-diastase</name> by 
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Jokichi_Takamine">TAKAMINE JÔKICHI</name> in 1892, the invention of the Toyoda power 
                        loom by <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Sakichi_Toyoda">TOYODA SAKICHI</name> in 1897, the extraction of adrenalin by 
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Jokichi_Takamine">Takamine Jôkichi</name> in 1901, the invention of the seasoning 
                        Ajinomoto (L-monosodium glutamate; MSG) by <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Kikunae_Ikeda">IKEDA KIKUNAE</name> 
                        (see <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Ajinomoto">AJINOMOTO CO, INC</name>) in 1908, the invention of KS steel 
                        by <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Kotaro_Honda">HONDA KÔTARÔ</name> in 1917, the development of a nitrogen fixation 
                        process for industrial use by the National Chemical Laboratory for Industry in 1920, and the invention of the Yagi antenna by 
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Hidetsugu_Yagi">YAGI HIDETSUGU</name> in 1925. </p><pb n="373"/><p> After <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/World_War_II">World War II</name> technology once again broadened beyond 
                        military technology, and the national policy on science and technology was directed toward adapting imported technology to Japanese 
                        needs and standards. The SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY AGENCY was established in 1956 to unify policies for science and technology. The 
                        <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Ministry_of_International_Trade_and_Industry">MINISTRY OF INTERNATIONAL TRADE 
                        AND INDUSTRY</name> provided guidance to prevent excessive competition and the payment of unreasonably high licensing fees in 
                        importing technology. The ministry has assisted in introducing foreign technology while protecting and developing native industry. For 
                        example, in the case of thermo-electric power plants, the government approved the import of the first plant but enforced the use of 
                        domestically built plants thereafter. 		</p><p> Dependence on imported technology remained heavy in the postwar period. Important sectors of industry which emerged after the war, 
                        such as polymer chemistry, electronics, and atomic energy, have leaned heavily on imported technology. Technological rationalization 
                        and automation of production in more established industries, such as iron, steel, and machinery, have also been heavily dependent on 
                        foreign technology. 		</p><p> Payment of royalties for imported technology has increased remarkably. Even in 1977, when 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> caught up with 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">American</name> technological levels, $800 million was being paid in 
                        compensation. Since there has been little export of technology, the balance of international payments in technology has been unfavorable. 
                        However, export of technology has been increasing with the rise of the technological level in 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name>. Royalties paid to 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> for technology amounted to only $300,000 in 1956, but this amount
                        had increased to $150 million by 1976, and the ratio of payments received to payments made reached 17 percent. In the early 1980s
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> continued to pay out a large amount of foreign currency because 
                        of its heavy dependence on imported technology; however, it would have required several times as much time and money to develop the 
                        same technology independently. 		</p><p><hi rend="bold">Characteristics of Japanese Technology</hi>---The Japanese dependence on imported technology does not imply a simple 
                        imitation of imported technology. The <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japanese_people">Japanese</name> have 
                        continuously endeavored not only to improve imported technology but to adapt it to fit new needs. For example, while all the 
                        fundamental technology for television, including television recording, has been based on foreign patents, Japanese engineers 
                        developed video recording for home use. 		</p><p> Japanese industry particularly stresses the development of applied technology, and the proportion of total research and development 
                        funds that is allocated to basic research is small. In 1974 it was only 6.3 percent, and most of this was, in actual fact, directed 
                        to the application and improvement of technology. See also RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT. 		</p><p> The major Japanese enterprises are in intense competition with each other and are anxious to introduce advanced technology from abroad
                        ahead of others. The technology introduced by major enterprises is also speedily adopted by the small and medium enterprises that 
                        operate as subcontractors to the larger enterprises. The subcontracting enterprises obtain new technological information promptly 
                        from their parent companies and introduce new technology with the financial and technological aid of the latter. 		</p><p><hi rend="italic">Creativity</hi>. Japanese engineers, so gifted in their ability to find, import, and improve new technology from 
                        abroad, are, however, weak in developing new technology through their own efforts. Although there is no real way to measure creativity 
                        and the latent ability to develop technology, in a white paper on the world economy issued in 1969 by the Economic Planning Agency in 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name>, an international comparison was made on the basis of the following 
                        eight indices: (1) the number of registered patents; (2) the ratio of payment to receipt in technological trade; (3) the ratio in total 
                        exports of technologically intensive industry; (4) the number of cases of successful industrialization of important new technology after 
                        1945; (5) the total expenditure for research; (6) the number of persons engaged in research and development; (7) the number of graduates
                        from schools of science and engineering; and (8) the number of computers installed. Combining these indices, the agency came up with a 
                        ratio for each country surveyed to the standard index (100) of the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">
                        United States</name>. According to this method, the rating of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name>
                        at the end of the 1960s was 19, comparable to <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/West_Germany">West Germany</name> but far
                        behind the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">United States</name>. 		</p><p><hi rend="bold">Recent Trends</hi>---When environmental pollution came under severe attack in the 1970s, the government set up strict 
                        environmental standards, which resulted in the development of desulfurization technology ahead of the
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Western_Europe">Western European countries</name>. In particular, the tightening of 
                        automobile emission standards has brought about the development of some of the cleanest automobile engines in the world 
                        (see LOW-POLLUTION ENGINES). 		</p><p> In the late 1970s and early 1980s new developments in the field of very large-scale integrated (VLSI) circuits were made in 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name>. VLSI with 64 kilobits were completed in 1977 through the joint 
                        research of the Telegraph and Telephone Public Corporation, Nippon Electric Co, and Fujitsu, Ltd. Then, under the guidance of the 
                        <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Ministry_of_International_Trade_and_Industry">Ministry of International Trade 
                        and Industry</name>, the VLSI Technology Research Association (a research group composed of Tôshiba Corporation, Nippon Electric Co,
                        Ltd, Hitachi, Fujitsû, Ltd, Mitsubishi Electric Corporation, and seven other companies) in 1980 completed an electron beam lithography 
                        system capable of drawing circuits with a width of 0.5 microns (5/10,000 millimeters). This technology has succeeded in increasing a 
                        hundredfold the capacity of semiconductors. 		</p><p><name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> caught up with the 
                        <name type="pace" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">United States</name> in labor productivity in the 1970s and has overtaken 
                        it in the technological level of certain production processes, as in the production of automobiles and television sets. 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> also has an advanced technology in such areas as the prevention of 
                        pollution and environmental science. There still exists, however, a substantial technological gap between the 
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/United_States">United States</name> and
                        <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japan">Japan</name> in such areas likely to be important in the future as atomic energy,
                        aerospace, and oceanography. See also TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENT; TECHNOLOGICAL INNOVATION; TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER. 		</p><p><hi rend="bold">Literature</hi>--- Ôshima Keiichi, "Science and Technology Policy in Japan's Economic Growth," Proceedings of the Fourth
                        Tsukuba International Symposium on the Role of the University in International Development (1977). UNESCO, ed, Technological Development 
                        in Japan (1971).  		</p><p> 			SHISHIDO Tosmo 		</p></div></div></body></text></TEI>