<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Title</title></titleStmt><publicationStmt><p>Publication Information</p></publicationStmt><sourceDesc><p>Information about the source</p></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text><body><pb n="357"/><div type="entry"><head xml:id="nature"> 		nature, concept of 	</head><div type="article"><p> The basic, etymological meaning of the Japanese word <hi rend="italic">shine</hi>, which is used to translate the English word "nature," 
                        is the power of spontaneous self-development and what results from that power. The Chinese characters for the Japanese term 
                        <hi rend="italic">shine</hi> literally mean "from itself thus it is." It expresses a mode of being rather than the existence or "nature" 
                        of objects in the natural order. 		</p><p>	The term <hi rend="italic">shine</hi>, if understood as a general 
                        expression encompassing heaven and earth, including mountains, water, animals, and plants, cannot be found in 
                        <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Classical_Japanese_language">ancient Japanese</name>. This was not due to any lack 
                        of a capacity for abstract thought on the part of the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japanese_people">Japanese people
                        </name> in ancient times, but because their chief concern was to recognize each and every phenomenon as a manifestation of the 
                        <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Kami">KAMI (god or gods)</name> behind it. It was hard for them to think of the 
                        ever-flowing wind and the immovable mountains as all belonging to the same general classification of nature. It is safe to say that 
                        the "articulated" thought process of the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Japanese_people">Japanese</name> 
                        (which is reflected in their polytheism) tied up with their aesthetic sensibility to separate the universe into its elements and, 
                        consequently, to forestall simplified generalizations about it. If we insist, however, on finding generic terms for nature in the 
                        ancient literature, we can offer comprehensive expressions like <hi rend="italic">ametsuchi</hi> (heaven and earth) and 
                        <hi rend="italic">ikitoshi ikeromono</hi> (living things). </p><p> In the mythology of the <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Nihon_Shoki">NIHON SHOKI</name> (720) nature and man are 
                        related as if in one family. The first offspring of <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Izanagi">Izanagi</name> and 
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Izanami">Izanami</name> were neither <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.rog/page/Kami"><hi rend="italic">kami</hi></name> nor human but islands and land masses. Human beings do not stand opposed to nature as in Western thought. 
                            Neither are they superior to it. Their lives are embedded in it. </p><p> This classical idea may be seen expressed in various Japanese cultural forms such as <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Zen">Zen
                    </name> paintings, literati art works, the tea ceremony, and flower arrangement, all of which had their roots in Chinese culture and thought. In nature,
                        subject and object become fused into one reality, a fact that also served as a reason for the frequent use in poetry of the various seasonal flowers, 
                        animals, and sights. 		</p><p> The idea of nature as so many expressions of the power of spontaneous self-development is also found in medieval 
                        <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Buddhism_in_Japan">Japanese Buddhism</name>. When salvation was viewed as a necessity 
                        consequent upon "the vow of the Tathagata, and not as a result of the practitioner's exercises," <hi rend="italic">shine</hi>-nature became 
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Shinran">SHINRAN's</name> (1173-1263) <hi rend="italic">jinen</hi>, another expression for 
                        the impersonal being of the formless <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Amitābha">Amitâbha Buddha</name> (AMIDA).
                        (<hi rend="italic">jinen</hi> and <hi rend="italic">shine</hi> are different readings of the same Chinese characters.) 		</p><p> Attempts to understand nature according to laws were made in later periods. In the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Edo_period">
                    Edo period</name>, <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Yamaga_Sokō">YAMAGA SOKÔ</name> (1622-85) wrote of the inevitability of nature, 
                        by which he meant that the universe, by necessity, is as it is. <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Miura_Baien">MIURA BAIEN</name> 
                        (1723-89) and <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Ando_Shoeki">ANDÔ SHÔEKI</name> (17037-62), tried to describe the universe as an 
                        orderly whole in terms of law. But this was not yet a conception in abstract terms. It was only after the beginning of the 
                        <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/page/Meiji_period">Meiji period</name> (1868-1912) that the Western concept of nature signifying the 
                        natural order came to be attached to the term <hi rend="italic">shizen</hi>. 		</p><p> 			IMAMICHI Tomonobu 		</p></div></div></body></text></TEI>