<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><teiHeader><fileDesc><titleStmt><title>Title</title></titleStmt><publicationStmt><p>Publication Information</p></publicationStmt><sourceDesc><p>Information about the source</p></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text><body><div type="entry"><head><term xml:id="ART"><hi rend="bold">ART</hi></term></head><div type="article"><p>,<gloss target="#ART" rend="unmarked"> a word in its most extended and most
                                                                                popular sense meaning everything which we distinguish from Nature</gloss>. Art
                                                                                and Nature are the two most comprehensive genera of which the human mind has
                                                                                formed the conception. Under the genus Nature, or the genus Art, we include all
                                                                                the phenomena of the universe. But as our conception of Nature is indeterminate
                                                                                and variable, so in some degree is our conception of Art. Nor does such
                                                                                ambiguity arise only because some modes of thought refer a greater number of the
                                                                                phenomena of the universe to the genus Nature, and others a greater number to
                                                                                the genus Art. It arises also because we do not strictly limit the one genus by
                                                                                the other. The range of the phenomena to which we point, when we say Art, is
                                                                                never very exactly determined by the range of the other phenomena which at the
                                                                                same time we tacitly refer to the order of Nature. Everybody understands the
                                                                                general meaning of a phrase like <cit><ref><name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Geoffrey_Chaucer">Chaucer's</name></ref><quote>"Nature ne Art ne koude him not amende"</quote></cit>, or <cit><ref><name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alexander_Pope">Pope's</name></ref><quote>"Blest with each grace of nature and of art"</quote></cit>. In such phrases we intend to designate familiarly as Nature all which
                                                                                exists independently of our study, forethought and exertion—in other words,
                                                                                those phenomena in ourselves or the world which we do not originate but find;
                                                                                and we intend to designate familiarly as Art all which we do not find but
                                                                                originate—or, in other words, the phenomena which we add by study, forethought
                                                                                and exertion to those existing independently of us. But we do not use these
                                                                                designations consistently. Sometimes we draw an arbitrary line in the action of
                                                                                individuals and societies, and say, Here Nature ends and Art begins—such a law,
                                                                                such a practice, such an industry even, is natural, and such another is
                                                                                artificial; calling those natural which happen spontaneously and without much
                                                                                reflection, and the others artificial. But this line different observers draw at
                                                                                different places. Sometimes we adopt views which waive the distinction
                                                                                altogether. One such view is that wherein all phenomena are regarded as equally
                                                                                natural, and the idea of Nature is extended so as to include <quote>"all the
                                                                                powers existing in either the outer or the inner world, and everything which
                                                                                exists by means of those powers"</quote>. In this view Art becomes a part of
                                                                                Nature. It is illustrated in the familiar passage of <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Shakespeare">Shakespeare</name>, where
                                                                                <name type="person">Polixenes</name> reminds <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Perdita_(The_Winter's_Tale)">Perdita</name>
                                                                                that</p></div><div type="poem"><lg><l>"Nature is made better by no mean,</l><l>But nature makes that mean : so, over that art</l><l>Which, you say, adds to nature, is an art</l><l>That nature makes." . . .</l></lg><lg><l>"This is an art</l><l>Which does mend nature, change it rather, but</l><l>The art itself is nature".</l></lg></div><div type="article"><p>A posthumous essay of <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Stuart_Mill">John Stuart Mill</name> contains a full philosophical
exposition and defence of this mode of regarding the
relations of Nature and Art. Defining Nature as above, and again
as a <quote>"collective name for all facts, actual and possible"</quote>, that
writer proceeds to say that such a definition
                  <quote>"is evidently inapplicable to some of the modes in which the word
                      is familiarly employed. For example, it entirely conflicts with the
                      common form of speech by which Nature is opposed to Art, and
                      natural to artificial. For in the sense of the word Nature which has
                      thus been defined, and which is the true scientific sense, Art is as
                      much Nature as anything else; and everything which is artificial is
                      natural—Art has no independent powers of its own: Art is but
                      the employment of the powers of Nature for an end. Phenomena
                      produced by human agency, no less than those which, as far as we
                      are concerned, are spontaneous, depend on the properties of the
                      elementary forces, or of the elementary substances and their compounds.
                      The united powers of the whole human race could not
                      create a new property of matter in general, or of any one of its species.
                      We can only take advantage for our purposes of the properties we
                      find. A ship floats by the same laws of specific gravity and equilibrium
                      as a tree uprooted by the wind and blown into the water.
                      The corn which men raise for food grows and produces its grain by
                      the same laws of vegetation by which the wild rose and the mountain
                      strawberry bring forth their flowers and fruit. A house stands and
                      holds together by the natural properties, the weight and cohesion
                      of the materials which compose it. A steam engine works by the
                      natural expansive force of steam, exerting a pressure upon one
                      part of a system of arrangements, which pressure, by the mechanical
                      properties of the lever, is transferred from that to another part,
                      where it raises the weight or removes the obstacle brought into connexion
                      with it. In these and all other artificial operations the
                      office of man is, as has often been remarked, a very limited one; it
                      consists of moving things into certain places. We move objects,
                      and by doing this, bring some things into contact which were separate,
                      or separate others which were in contact; and by this simple change
                      of place, natural forces previously dormant are called into action,
                      and produce the desired effect. Even the volition which designs,
                      the intelligence which contrives, and the muscular force which
                      executes these movements, are themselves powers of Nature"</quote>.
Another mode of thought, in some sort complementary to
the last, is based on the analogy which the operations of forces
external to a man bear to the operations of man himself. Study,
forethought and exertion are assigned to Nature, and her
operations are called operations of Art. This view was familiar
to ancient systems of philosophy, and especially to that of
the Stoics. According to the report of 
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cicero">Cicero</name>, Nature as conceived
                  by <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zeno_of_Citium">Zeno</name> was a fire, and at the same time a voluntary agent
having the power or art of creating things with regularity and
design (<quote>"naturam esse ignem artificiosum ad gignendum progredientem
via"</quote>) . To this fire not merely creative force and
                      <pb n="657"/>
systematic action were ascribed, but actual personality. Nature
was <quote>"non artificiosa solum, sed plane artifex"</quote>. <quote>"That which
    in the works of human art is done by hands, is done with much
    greater art by Nature, that is, by a fire which exercises an art
    and is the teacher of other arts"</quote>. This conception of Nature
as an all-generating fire, and at the same time as a personal
artist both teaching and including in her own activity all the
human arts, on the one hand may be said, with <name type="person">Polixenes</name> and
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Stuart_Mill">J.S. Mill</name>, to merge Art in Nature ; but on the other hand it
finds the essence of Nature in the resemblance of her operations
to those of Art. <quote>"It is the <hi rend="italic">proprium</hi> of art,"</quote> according to the
                  same system, <quote>"to create and beget,"</quote> and the reasoning proceeds
—Nature creates and begets, therefore Nature is an artist or
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Demiurge">Demiurgus</name>. A kindred view is set forth by 
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Browne">Sir Thomas Browne</name>
                      in the <title key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Religio_Medici"><hi rend="italic">Religio Medici</hi></title>, when he declares that 
                  <quote>"all things are artificial; for Nature is the Art of God"</quote>.
But these modes of thought, according to which, on the one
hand, the processes of Art are included among processes of
Nature, or on the other the processes of Nature among the processes
of Art, are exceptional. In ordinary use the two conceptions,
each of them somewhat vague and inexact, are antithetical.
Their antithesis was what <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Samuel_Johnson">Dr Johnson</name> had chiefly in his mind
when he defined Art as <quote>"the power of doing something which
    is not taught by Nature or by instinct"</quote>. But this definition
is insufficient, because the abstract word Art, whether used
of all arts at once or of one at a time, is a name not only for the
power of doing something, but for the exercise of the power;
and not only for the exercise of the power, but for the rules
according to which it is exercised; and not only for the rules,
but for the result. Painting, for instance, is an art, and the word
connotes not only the power to paint, but the act of painting;
and not only the act, but the laws for performing the act rightly;
and not only all these, but the-material consequences of the
act or the thing painted. So of agriculture, navigation and
the rest. Exception might also be taken to 
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Samuel_Johnson">Dr Johnson's</name> definition
on the ground that it excludes all actions of instinct from
the genus Art, whereas usage has in more languages than one
given the name of Art to several of those ingenuities in the lower
animals which popular theory at the same time declares to be
instinctive. <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dante_Alighieri">Dante</name>, for instance, speaks of boughs shaken by the
wind, but not so violently as to make the birds forgo their Art—</p></div><div type="poem"><lg><l>"Non perd dal lor esser dritto sparte</l><l>Tanto, che gl' augelletti per le cime</l><l>Lasciasser d' opcrar ogni lor <hi rend="italic">arte</hi>."</l></lg></div><div type="article"><p>
                  And <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bernard_le_Bovier_de_Fontenelle">Fontenelle</name>, speaking in the language not of poetry but
                  of science :—<quote>"Most animals—as, for instance, bees, spiders
                      and beavers—have a kind of art peculiar to themselves; but
                      each race of animals has no more than one art, and this one
                      has had no first inventor among the race. Man, on the other
                      hand, has an infinity of different arts which were not born with
                      his race, and of which the glory is his own"</quote>. 
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Samuel_Johnson">Dr Johnson</name> might
reply that those properties of variety and of originality or individual
invention, which <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bernard_le_Bovier_de_Fontenelle">Fontenelle</name> himself alleges in the
ingenuities of man but not in those of the lower animals, are
sufficient to make a generic difference, and to establish the
impropriety of calling a honeycomb or a spider's web a work
of Art. It is not our purpose to trespass on ground so debateable
as that of the nature of consciousness in the lower animals.
Enough that when we use the term Art of any action, it is because
we are thinking of properties in the action from which we infer,
whether justly or not, that the agent voluntarily and designedly
puts forth skill for known ends and by regular and uniform
methods. If, then, we were called upon to frame a general
definition of Art, giving the word its widest and most comprehensive
meaning, it would run thus :—<hi rend="italic">Every regulated operation
    or dexterity by which organized beings pursue ends which they know
    beforehand, together with the rules and the result of every such
    operation or dexterity</hi>.
Here it will be well to consider very briefly the natural history
of the name which has been given to this very comprehensive
conception by the principal branches of civilized mankind.
Our own word Art the English language has taken, as all the
Romance languages of modern Europe have taken theirs, directly
from the Latin. The Latin <term xml:lang="la"><hi rend="italic">ars</hi></term>, according to the prevailing
opinion of philologists, proceeds from a root AR, of which the
primitive signification was to put or fit things together, and
which is to be found in a large family of Greek words. The
Greek <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">τέχυη</hi></term> the name both for arts in the particular and art
                  in the abstract, is by its root related both to <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">τέκ-τωυ</hi></term> and
                  <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">τέκ-υου</hi></term>, and thus contains the allied ideas of making and begetting.
                  The <term xml:lang="la"><hi rend="italic">proprium</hi></term> of art in the logic of the Stoics, 
                  <quote>"to create and beget"</quote>, was strictly in accordance with this etymology.
                  The Teutonic <term xml:lang="de"><hi rend="italic">Kunst</hi></term> is formed from <hi rend="italic">können</hi>, 
                  and <hi rend="italic">können</hi> is
                  developed from a primitive <hi rend="italic">Ich kann</hi>. In <hi rend="italic">kann</hi> philology is
inclined to recognize a preterite form of a lost verb, of which
we find the traces in <hi rend="italic">Kin-d</hi>, a child ; and the form <hi rend="italic">Ich kann</hi>
thus meaning originally "I begot," contains the germ of the two
several developments,—<hi rend="italic">können</hi>, "to be master," "to be able,"
                  and <hi rend="italic">kennen</hi>, "to know." We thus see that the chief Indo-
European languages have with one consent extended a name for
the most elementary exercise of a constructive or productive
power, till that name has covered the whole range of the skilled
and deliberate operations of sentient beings.
In proportion as men left out of sight the idea of creation, of
constructing or producing, <q>"artificiosum esse ad gignendum"</q>,
which is the primitive half of this extended notion, and attended
only to the idea of skill, of proceeding by regular and disciplined
methods, <q>"progredi via,"</q> which is the superadded half, the
whole notion Art, and the name for it, might become subject to
a process of thought which, if analysed, would be like this:—
What is done by regular and disciplined methods is Art; facts
are observed and classified, and a systematic view of the order
of the universe obtained, by regular and disciplined methods;
the observing and classifying of facts, and obtaining a systematic
view of the order of the universe, is therefore Art. To a partial
extent this did unconsciously take place. Science, of which the
essence is only in knowledge and theory, came to be spoken of as
Art, of which the essence is all in practice and production.
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cicero">Cicero</name>, 
                  notwithstanding his citation of the Stoical dictum that
practice and production were of the essence of Art, elsewhere
divides Art into two kinds—one by which things are only
contemplated in the mind, another by which something is produced
and done. (<cit><quote>"Quumque artium aliud eiusmodi sit, ut
    tantummodo rem cernat; aliud, ut moliatur aliquid et faciat."</quote><ref>-<bibl><title><hi rend="italic">Acad.</hi></title> ii. 7.</bibl></ref></cit>) 
                  Of the former kind his instance is geometry; of
the latter the art of playing on the lyre. Now geometry, understanding
by geometry an acquisition of the mind, that is, a
collected body of observations and deductions concerning the
properties of space and magnitude, is a science and not an art;
although there is an art of the geometer, which is the skill by
which he solves any given problem in his science, and the rules
of that skill, and his exertion in putting it forth. And so every
science has its instrumental art or practical discipline; and in
as far as the word Art is used only of the practical discipline or
dexterity of the geometer, the astronomer, the logician, the
grammarian, or other person whose business it is to collect and
classify facts for contemplation, in so far the usage is just. The
same justification may be extended to another usage, whereby
in Latin, and some of its derivative languages, the name Art came
to be transferred in a concrete sense to the body of rules, the
written code or manual, which lays down the discipline and
regulates the dexterity; as <hi rend="italic">ars grammatica, ars logica, ars rhetorica</hi>
and the rest. But when the word is stretched so as to mean the
sciences, as theoretical acquisitions of the mind, that meaning is
illegitimate. Whether or not <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cicero">Cicero</name>, in the passage above quoted,
had in his mind the science of geometry as a collected body of
observations and deductions, it is certain that the Ciceronian
phrase of the <hi rend="italic">liberal arts</hi>, the <hi rend="italic">ingenuous arts</hi>, both in Latin and
its derivatives or translations in modern speech, has been used
currently to denote the sciences themselves, and not merely
the disciplines instrumental to them. The <hi rend="italic">trivium</hi> and the
                  <hi rend="italic">quadrivium</hi> (grammar, logic and rhetoric—geometry, astronomy,
music and arithmetic) have been habitually called arts, when
some of them have been named in that sense in which they mean
                  <pb n="658"/>
not arts but sciences, <q>"only contemplating things in the mind."</q>
Hence the nomenclature, history and practical organization,
especially in Britain, of one great division of university studies:
the division of <q>"arts,"</q> with its <q>"faculty,"</q> its examinations, and
its degrees.
In the German language the words for Art and Science have in
general been loosely interchanged. The etymology of the word
for Art secured a long continuance for this ambiguity. <term xml:lang="de"><hi rend="italic">Kunst</hi></term>
was employed indiscriminately in both the senses of the primitive
                  <hi rend="italic">Ich kann</hi>, to signify what I know, or Science, and what I can do,
or Art. It was not till the end of the 17th century that a separate
word for Science, the modern <term xml:lang="de"><hi rend="italic">Wissenschaft</hi></term>, came into use.
                  On the other hand, the Greek word <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">τέχυη</hi></term>, with its distinct
suggestion of the root signification to make or get, acted probably
as a safeguard against this tendency. The distinction between
                  <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">τέχυη</hi></term>, Art or practice, and 
                  <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">έπιστήμη</hi></term>, knowledge or Science, is
observed, though not systematically, in Greek philosophy. But
for our present purpose, that of making clear the true relation
between the one conception and the other, further quotation is
rendered superfluous by the discussion the subject has received
at the hands of the modern writer already quoted. Between Art,
of which we practise the rules, and Science, of which we entertain
the doctrines, <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Stuart_Mill">J.S. Mill</name> establishes the difference in the simplest
shape, by pointing out that one grammatical mood is proper for
the conclusions of Science, and another for those of Art. Science
enunciates her conclusions in the indicative mood, whereas
                  <quote>"the imperative is the characteristic of Art, as distinguished
                      from Science."</quote> And as Art utters her conclusions in her own
form, so she supplies the substance of her own major premise.
                  <quote>"Every art has one first principle, or general major premise, not
                      borrowed from science, that which enunciates the object aimed at,
                      and affirms it to be a desirable object. The builder's art assumes
                      that it is desirable to have buildings; architecture (as one of the
                      fine arts) that it is desirable to have them beautiful and imposing.
                      The hygienic and medical arts assume, the one that the preservation
                      of health, the other that the cure of disease, are fitting and desirable
                      ends. These are not propositions of science. Propositions of science
                      assert a matter of fact—an existence, a co-existence, a succession,
                      or a resemblance. The propositions now spoken of do not assert
                      that anything is, but enjoin or recommend that something should
                      be. They are a class by themselves. A proposition of which the
                      predicate is expressed by the words <hi rend="italic">ought</hi> or <hi rend="italic">should be</hi> is generically
                      different from one which is expressed by <hi rend="italic">is</hi> or <hi rend="italic">will be</hi>."</quote>
And the logical relation of Art and Science, in other words,
the manner of framing the intermediate member between the
general major premise of Art and its imperative conclusion, is
thus defined:—
                  <cit><quote>"The Art [in any given case] proposes to itself an end to be
                      attained, defines the end, and hands it over to the Science. The
                      Science receives it, considers it as a phenomenon or effect to be
                      studied, and having investigated its causes and conditions, sends
                      it back to Art with a theorem of the causes and combinations by
                      which it could be produced. Art then examines these combinations
                      of circumstances, and according as any of them are or are not in
                      human power, pronounces the end attainable or not. The only one
                      of the premises, therefore, which Art supplies, is the original major
                      premise, which asserts that the attainment of the given end is
                      desirable. Science, then, lends to Art the proposition (obtained by
                      a series of inductions or deductions) that the performance of certain
                      actions will attain the end. From these premises Art concludes that
                      the performance of these actions is desirable, and finding it also
                      practicable, converts the theorem into a rule or precept. ... The
                      grounds, then, of every rule of Art are to be found in the theorems
                      of Science. An Art, or a body of Art, consists of the rules, together
                      with as much of the speculative propositions as comprises the justification
                      of these rules. The complete Art of any matter includes a
                      selection of such a portion from the Science as is necessary to show
                      on what conditions the effects, which the Art aims at producing,
                      depend. And Art in general consists of the truths of Science arranged
                      in the most convenient order for practice, instead of the order which
                      is most convenient for thought. Science groups and arranges its
                      truths so as to enable us to take in at one view as much as possible
                      of the general order of the universe. Art, though it must assume the
                      same general laws, follows them only into such of their detailed
                      consequences as have led to the formation of rules of conduct, and
                      brings together from parts of the field of Science most remote from
                      one another, the truths relating to the production of the different and
                      heterogeneous causes necessary to each effect which the exigencies
                      of practical life require to be produced."</quote><ref>—(<bibl><title>Mill's <hi rend="italic">Logic</hi></title>, vol. ii. pp.
                          542-549</bibl>)-</ref></cit>
The whole discussion may be summed up thus. Science
consists in knowing, Art consists in doing. What I must do in
order to know, is Art subservient to Science: what I must know
in order to do, is Science subservient to Art.
Art, then, is defined by two broad distinctions: first, its
popular distinction from Nature; and next, its practical and
theoretic distinction from Science. Both of these distinctions
are observed in the terms of our definition given above. Within
the proper limits of this definition, the conception of Art, and
the use of the word for it, have undergone sundry variations.
These variations correspond to certain vicissitudes or developments
in the order of historical facts and in society. The
requirements of society, stimulating the ingenuity of its individual
members, have led to the invention of arts and groups of arts,
constantly progressing, with the progress of civilization, in
number, in complexity, and in resource. The religious imagination
of early societies, who find themselves in possession of such
an art or group of arts, forgets the history of the invention, and
assigns it to the inspiration or special grace of some god or hero.
So the Greeks assigned the arts of agriculture to 
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Triptolemus">Triptolemus</name>,
                  those of spinning and navigation to <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/ATHENA">Athena</name>, and of music to
                  <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Apollo">Apollo</name>. At one stage of civilization one art or group of arts is
held in higher esteem, another at another. In societies, like most
of those of the ancient world, where slaves were employed in
domestic service, and upon the handicrafts supplying the
immediate utilities of life—food, shelter and clothing—these
constituted a group of servile arts. The arts of husbandry or
agriculture, on the other hand, have alternately been regarded
as servile and as honourable according as their exercise has been
in the hands of a subject class, as under feudal institutions, or,
as under the Roman republic, of free cultivators. Under feudal
institutions, or in a society in a state of permanent war, the allied
arts of war and of government have been held the only honourable
class. In commercial states, like the republics of Italy, the arts
of gain, or of production (other than agricultural) and distribution,
have made good their title to equal estimation and greater power
beside the art of captains. But among peaceful arts, industries
or trades, some have always been held to be of higher and others
of lower rank; the higher rank being assigned to those that
required larger operations, higher training, or more thoughtful
conduct, and yielded ampler returns—the lower rank to those
which called for simple manual exercise, especially if such
exercise was of a disagreeable or degrading kind. In the cities
of Italy, where both commerce and manufactures were for the
first time organized on a considerable scale, 
the name <term xml:lang="it"><hi rend="italic">arte</hi></term>, Art,
was retained to designate the gilds or corporations by which the
several industries were exercised; and, according to the nature
of the industry, the art was classed as higher or lower (<term xml:lang="it"><hi rend="italic">maggiore</hi></term>
                  and <term xml:lang="it"><hi rend="italic">minore</hi></term>).
The arts of which we have hitherto spoken have arisen from
positive requirements, and supply what are strictly utilities, in
societies; not excluding the art of war, at least so far as concerns
one-half of war, the defensive half. But war continued to be
an honourable pursuit, because it was a pursuit associated
with birth, power and wealth, as well as with the virtue of
courage, in cases where it had no longer the plea of utility, but
was purely aggressive or predatory; and the arts of the chase
have stood in this respect in an analogous position to those
of war.
There are other arts which have not had their origin in positive
practical needs, but have been practised from the first for
pleasure or amusement. The most primitive human beings of
whom we have any knowledge, the cave-dwellers of the palaeolithic
period, had not only the useful art of chipping stones into
spear-heads, knife-heads and arrow-heads, and making shafts
or handles of these implements out of bone; they had also the
ornamental art of scratching upon the bone handle the outlines
of the animals they saw—mammoth, rhinoceros or reindeer—or
of carving such a handle into a rude resemblance of one of these
animals. Here we have a skill exercised, in the first case, for pure
fancy or pleasure, and in the second, for adding an element of
fancy or pleasure to an element of utility. Here, therefore, is the
                  <pb n="659"/>
germ of all those arts which produce imitations of natural objects
for purposes of entertainment or delight, as painting, sculpture,
and their subordinates; and of all those which fashion useful
objects in one way rather than another because the one way gives
pleasure and the other does not, as architecture and the subordinate
decorative arts of furniture, pottery and the rest. Arts that
work in a kindred way with different materials are those of
dancing and music. Dancing works with the physical movements
of human beings. Music works with sound. Between that
imitative and plastic group, and the group of these which only
produce motion or sound and pass away, there is the intermediate
group of eloquence and the drama, which deal with the
expression of human feeling in spoken words and acted gestures.
There is also the comprehensive art of poetry, which works with
the material of written words, and can ideally represent the
whole material of human life and experience. Of all these arts
the end is not use but pleasure, or pleasure before use, or at least
pleasure and use conjointly. In modern language, there has
grown up a usage which has put them into a class by themselves
under the name of the Fine Arts, as distinguished from the
Useful or Mechanical Arts. (See AESTHETICS and FINE ARTS.)
Nay more, to them alone is often appropriated the use of the
generic word Art, as if they and they only were the arts 
                  <term xml:lang="grc"><hi rend="italic">κατ’έξοχήν</hi></term>.
And further yet, custom has reduced the number which the
class-word is meant to include. When Art and the works of Art
are now currently spoken of in this sense, not even music or
poetry is frequently denoted, but only architecture, sculpture
and painting by themselves, or with their subordinate and
decorative branches. In correspondence with this usage,
another usage has removed from the class of <hi rend="italic">arts</hi>, and put into a
contrasted class of <hi rend="italic">manufactures</hi>, a large number of industries
and their products, to which the generic term Art, according
to our definition, properly applies. The definition covers the
                  <hi rend="italic">mechanical</hi> arts, which can be efficiently exercised by mere
trained habit, rote or calculation, just as well as the fine arts,
which have to be exercised by a higher order of powers. But
the word Art, becoming appropriated to the fine arts, has been
treated as if it necessarily carried along with it, and as if works
to be called works of art must necessarily possess, the attributes
of free individual skill and invention, expressing themselves in
ever new combinations of pleasurable contrivance, and seeking
perfection not as a means towards some ulterior practical end
but as an ideal end in itself.</p></div><byline>(S. C.)</byline></div></body></text></TEI>