<TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Cefu tongzong 策府統宗 (Comprehensive Summary of the Imperial Library)</title>
                <editor>Research Project "Hidden Grammars of Transculturality - Migrations of Encyclopedic Knowledge and Power"</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Project Coordination</resp>
                    <name xml:id="BM">Barbara Mittler</name>
                    <name xml:id="MH">Madeleine Herren-Oesch</name>
                    <name xml:id="JK">Joachim Kurtz</name>
                    <name xml:id="KMW">Kaja Mueller-Wang</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Technical supervision and file administration</resp>
                    <name xml:id="JP">Jens Østergaard Petersen</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>TEI Header</resp>
                    <name xml:id="OS">Oliver Schulz</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cluster of Excellence "Asia and Europe in a Global Context"</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Heidelberg University</pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Karl Jaspers Centre for Advanced Transcultural Studies</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Voßstraße 2, Building 4400</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>69115 Heidelberg</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Germany</addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Cefu tongzong 策府統宗 (Comprehensive Summary of the Imperial Library)</title>
                        <author>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#LiuChangling">Liu Changling 劉昌齡</name>
                        </author>                        
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <edition>Reprints in 1891 and 1897.</edition>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Hongwen shuju 鴻文書局</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Shanghai 上海</pubPlace>
                        <date>Guangxu 15[1889]</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                 </biblFull>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <settlement>Heidelberg University</settlement>
                        <repository>Library of the Institute of Chinese Studies</repository>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>
                        <p>Size: 12,2cm * 7.25cm </p>
                        <p>Volumes: 65 juan</p>
                        <p>Script: Print</p>
                        <p>Illustrations: None.</p>
                        <p>The characters are written in about 30 columns with almost no space above and to the side, it very much resembles classical texts.</p>
                    </physDesc>
                    <msPart>
                        <altIdentifier>
                            <idno/>
                        </altIdentifier>
                        <msContents>
                            <p>Lemma-organization: The content of the book is ordered into 65 juan. The ordering of the juan is a mix of traditional and modern elements, 
                                whereby the thematically related lemmata are to be found therein. The lemmata of each juan do not follow a stroke count arrangement.</p>
                            <p>Table of contents: Located at the beginning of the book, it is a listing of each juan with each lemma. Not very helpful to get an orientation at the first sight.</p>
                            <p>Index: none.</p>
                            <p>Bibliography: yes</p>
                            <p>Contents: The book offers the information which had been important for the exams. Many written works are mentioned and explained, but also issues like traditional military ranks.   
                            The listed books often come with the number of its juan.</p>
                        </msContents>
                        <history>
                            <p>A scan of the work is available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <settingDesc>
                <p>According to the preface Liu was not satisfied with the book cexue dacheng 策學大成 by Cai Mei'an, he therefore wanted to correct its mistakes and wrote a new work. In this undertaking he was supported by many erudite scholars. 
                   </p></settingDesc>
            <textDesc>
                <channel mode="w">print</channel>
                <constitution type="single">The text is ordered into many lemmata, which are mostly comparatively short.                     
                </constitution>
                <derivation type="abridgment"></derivation>
                <domain type="education"/>
                <factuality type="fact"/>
                <interaction type="none" active="plural" passive="world"></interaction>
                <preparedness type="none"/>
                <purpose type="inform" degree="high">The book should be a preparatory tool for students taking the exams.</purpose>
                <purpose type="entertain" degree="low"/>
            </textDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="zh" usage="100">Chinese</language>                
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Scans available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
            <p>Digitalization by Formax BPO Beijing Inc., special instructions for typing Chinese texts and encyclopedias developed by
                Wolfgang Schmidle et. al. at Max Planck Institute for the History of Science, Berlin. 
                Transformation of the digitized raw texts into TEI done by Wolfgang Schmidle. 
                TEI Header and mark-ups inserted by project members at Heidelberg University.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-09-05" who="#OS">created</change>
            <change when="2011-09-05" who="#OS">Questionnaire info added to TEI header</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="entry"/>       
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>