<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">The Penny Cyclopaedia of The Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge. First edition, 1833-1843.</title>
                <title type="sub">An electronic edition of excerpts for transcultural research</title>
                <editor>Research Project "Hidden Grammars of Transculturality - Migrations of Encyclopedic Knowledge and Power"</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Project Coordination</resp>
                    <name xml:id="BM">Barbara Mittler</name>
                    <name xml:id="MH">Madeleine Herren-Oesch</name>
                    <name xml:id="JK">Joachim Kurtz</name>
                    <name xml:id="KMW">Kaja Mueller-Wang</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Technical supervision and file administration</resp>
                    <name xml:id="JP">Jens Petersen</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Proof-reading, Mark-up</resp>
                    <name xml:id="CS">Charlotte Schäfer</name>
                    <name xml:id="JL">Jonathan Link</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cluster of Excellence "Asia and Europe in a Global Context"</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Heidelberg University</pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Karl Jaspers Centre for Advanced Transcultural Studies</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Voßstraße 2, Building 4400</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>69115 Heidelberg</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Germany</addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>The Penny Cyclopaedia of The Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge</title>
                        <editor>The Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge</editor>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <edition>First Edition</edition>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Charles Knight</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                        <date>1833-1843</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>The Penny Cyclopædia of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge was a multi-volume 
                                        encyclopedia edited by George Long and published by Charles Knight alongside the Penny Magazine, 
                                        London 1833 –1843.</p>
                            <p>The Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge, founded in 1826, was an organisation that 
                                              published inexpensive texts intended to adapt scientific and similarly high-minded material 
                                              for the rapidly expanding reading public.</p>
                            <p>In the preface dating from 13th November 1833 the editors announce after the completion of the 
                                              first volume, that two partial publications of futher volumes will be published weekly. 
                                              One part is to cost Ninepence. On the 1st of September 1834 the seconc volume is supposed 
                                              to be finished, consisting of nine of these Ninepence Parts; bound in a hardcopy it is to 
                                              cost Seven Shillings and Sixpence. The announce the publication of another volume every 
                                              eight months. </p>
                        </note>
                        <note>Scans from Google.</note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-07-12" who="#KMW">update of TEI header, subtype added, xml:id corrected</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="entry" subtype="education">
                <head>
                    <term xml:id="Education">Education.</term>
                </head>
                <p>
                    <gloss target="#Education" rend="unmarked">is the art of preparing youth for the business
        of after-life.</gloss> This is not offered as a complete or exact
        definition; it is only proposed as sufficient to indicate in a
        general way the subject matter here under discussion.</p>
                <p>In every nation, even those called uncivilized, there are,
          and necessarily must be, certain practices and usages according
          to which children are instructed in those things which
          are to form the occupation of their future life ; and every
          civilized nation, and, we may presume, nations also called
          uncivilized, have some general and collective term by which
          they express this process of instruction.In the European
          languages derived from the <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Latin">Latin</name>, and in others that have
          a mixture of that language, the general term is Education.
          It is not important at present to consider the more or less
          precise notions attached to this or any other equivalent
          word, but it is enough to observe, that, as the language of
          every nation possesses such a term, it is a universal truth
          that all nations or societies of men admit that there is something
          which is expressed by the comprehensive term Education,
          or by some equivalent term. But like all other
          general terms which have been long in use, this term Education
          comprehends within the general meaning already
          assigned to it a great number of particulars, which are
          conceived by various people in such different modes and
          degrees and in such varying amount as to the number of
          the particulars, some nations or individuals conceiving a
          certain set of particulars as essential to the term, others,
          conceiving a different set of particulars as essentials, and
          others again conceiving the same particulars in such different
          ways, that two or more persons agreeing in their
          general description of the term might very probably, in
          descending into the enumeration of the particulars, find
          themselves completely at variance with one another. This
          remark possesses no claim to novelty, but it is not on that
          account the less important. The discrepancy just stated is
          apparent not only as to such general terms as education,
          government right, duty, and numerous otoer such words,
          the analysis of which can only be successfully attempted by
          those who are accustomed to that kind of inquiry, but it is
          perceived and occurs even in things obvious to the senses,
          which consist of a number of parts, sucb as a machine,
          or any other compound thing. The general use of a machine,
          as a mill, for instance, is conceived in the same way
          by all, by the miller and by persons who know nothing
          more about the mill than that it is used for grinding corn.
          As to the particulars, there may be all imaginable discrepancies
          among the persons who are only acquainted with
          the general purpose of the mill. But discrepancies as to
          the mode in which the several parts of a thing and the uses
          of the several parts are conceived, are generally discrepancies
          to be referred to the <hi rend="italic">inaccuracy</hi> of the conceptions;
          they are, in fact only errors, not the same but about the
          same thing. The more completely a large number of persons
          approach to harmony in their whole views as to this
          machine, the nearer, as a general rule, do their several views
          approach to accuracy; it being ofthe nature of truth to produce
          a harmony of opinion, the truth being one and invariable;
          and it being ofthe nature of error to admit of more
          varieties than man has yet conceived, inasmuch as men yet
          unborn will conceive errors never conceived before.</p>
                <p>The same holds good as to Education which holds good of
          the machine. The <hi rend="italic">general</hi> use, the <hi rend="italic">general</hi> object of Education
          is roughly and rightly conceived by all persons to
          whom the name is familiar; but the great contrariety
          which exists among mankind as to the particulars which
          they conceive as entering into and forming a part of this
          term, and as to their mode of conceiving the same, proves
          either that all are still wrong as to their particular conceptions
          of this term, or that hitherto no means have been
          discovered of producing a general harmony of opinion, or
          in other words, of approaching to the truth. And here
          there is no person, or class of persons, who, as in the case
          of the miller, is or are allowed to be an authority competent
          to decide between conflicting opinions.</p>
                <p>In every society, Education (in what particular manner
          conceived by any particular society is of no importance to
          our present inquiry) is, as a <hi rend="italic">general</hi> rule, and must necessarily
          be, subjected to the positive law of the society, and to
          that assemblage of opinions, customs, and habits which is
          not inappropriately called by some writers the Positive Morality
          of Society, or the Law of Opinion. This truth, or
          truism, as some may call it is the basis of every inquiry
          into Education. In no country can there exist as a <hi rend="italic">general</hi>
          rule, an Education, whether it be good or bad, not subordinate
          to the law as above explained: for if such Education did
          exist the form of that society or political system could not
          co-exist with it One or the other must be changed, so
          that on the whole there must at last result a harmony, and
          not a discord. In every country then there does exist Education,
          either directed by and subordinate to the Positive
          Law and Positive Morality of that country, or there is an
          Education not so directed and subordinate, and consequently
          inconsistent with the continuance of that political system<pb n="1"/>in which it exists. But such an anomaly, if found anywhere,
          should not be allowed to exist, because it is inconsistent
          with the continued existence of the society in which
          it has established itself; and if such an Education does
          exist and can maintain itself in a society, against the will
          of that society, such a society is not a sovereign and independent
          society, but is in a state of anarchy. Education
          then should be in harmony with aud subordinate to
          the political system: it should be part of it; and whether
          the political system is called by the name good or bad, if
          that political system is to continue, Education must not be
          opposed to it but just be a part of it. From this it follows
          that the question, What is the best Education? involves the
          question, What is the best political system? and that question
          again cannot be answered without considering what
          are the circumstances of the particular nation or society as
          to which we inquire what is the best political system. Recollecting
          however that the question of the best Education
          and of the best political system cannot be discussed apart
          because, as we have shown, Education is a part of the system,
          still we can consider several important questions quite
          as fully as if the former question were out of the way.
          One is, the political system being given, what ought the
          Education to be?</p>
                <p>And, how far is it the business of the state to direct,
        control, and encourage that Education?</p>
                <p>A man (under which term we include woman) has two
          distinct relations or classes of relations towards the state:
          one comprehends his duties as a citizen, wherein he is or
          ought to be wholly subordinate to the state; the other
          comprehends all his functions as a producer and enjoyer of
          wealth, wherein he has or ought to have all freedom that is
          not inconsistent with the proper discharge of his duties as a
          citizen. It is barely necessary to state this proposition in
          order to perceive that his Education as a citizen should be
          directed by the state. To suppose any other directing power,
          any power for instance which may educate him in principles
          opposed to the polity of which he is to form a part is to
          suppose an inconsistency which, in discussing any question
          involving principles, we always intend to avoid.</p>
                <p>His Education then as a citizen, it must be admitted,
          ought to be under the superintendence of the state; but
          <hi rend="italic">how</hi> ought the state to exercise this superintendence?
          It is not our purpose to attempt to answer this question,
          which involves tbe consideration of some of the most difficult
          questions in legislation. It is our object here to present
          the questions which it belongs to the civilization of the
          present and future ages to solve \ to show <hi rend="italic">what</hi> is to be
          done, not <hi rend="italic">how</hi> it is to be done.</p>
                <p>But we may answer the question so far as this: the state
          having the superintendence of the citizen's Education, must
          have the superintendence of those who direct that Education; 
          in other words, must direct those who are to carry its
          purposes into effect. The body of teachers therefore must
          be formed by, or, at least must be under the superintendence
          of the state. Unless this fundamental truth is admitted
          and acted on, the state cannot effectually direct or
          superintend the Education of its citizens.</p>
                <p>Every branch of this inquiry into Education runs out into
          other branches almost innumerable, till we find that the
          solution of this important question involves the solution of
          the greater part of those questions which occupy or ought
          to occupy a legislative body. For this reason, as above
          stated, we cannot attempt to answer in its full extent <hi rend="italic">how</hi>
          the state must direct the Education of its citizens, because
          this question involves the consideration of how far tbe direction
          and control of the state should be a matter of positive
          law imperative on all, how far and with respect to what particular
          matters it should encourage and give facilities only,
          how far it should act by penalties or punishment how far
          it should allow individuals or associations of individuals to
          teach or direct teaching according to their own will and
          judgment, or, to express the last question in other words,
          whether and to what extent the state should allow competition
          in Education?</p>
                <p>To these questions, and more especially to the last, the
          answer is in general terms, that the <hi rend="italic">general</hi> interest considered
          in all its bearings, must determine what and how much
          the state must do. This answer may be said to determine
          nothing. It is true it determines no particular thing, but
          it determines the principle by which all particular measures
          must be tested; and it would not be difficult to select instances
          even from our legislation, where enactments relating, 
          to places of education have been made with a view to particular
          interests only, without a reference to all the bearings
          of the question, and which, consequently, if tried by the
          test above given, would be found to be mischievous. As to
          the last question the answer more particularly is, that
          individual competition must not be destroyed. It is possible
          to reconcile the two principles of state direction and control
          and individual competition. The state may allow no
          person to teach without being examined and registered:
          such register will show if he has been trained under the
          superintendence of the state or not. This fact being established,
          it may be left to individuals or associations of individuals
          to employ what teachers they please. In all the
          schools founded by the state, in all schools under the superintendence
          of the state (to which latter class belong nearly all
          charitable foundations, and all such foundations which are
          not under the superintendence of the state ought consistently
          with the general principles already laid down, to be
          brought under that superintendence), it follows as a matter
          of course that none but teachers trained by the state should
          be appointed. The selection of the teachers, out of the
          whole authorized body, for any particular school of the
          class just described, may be safely left to the local authorities
          who have the immediate superintendence of these
          schools.</p>
                <p>If the principle that a state ought to exercise the superintendence
          of the Education of its citizens as citizens be admitted,
          it may be asked, how far and to what branches of
          knowledge does this extend? To this we reply that a precise
          answer can only be given by the legislature of each
          country, and the Question cannot be answered without many
          years of labour and perhaps without many experiments. But
          it follows from the principles already laid down that no citizen
          ought to exercise any function of government or he
          intrusted with the exercise of any power delegated by tho
          state, without having received <hi rend="italic">some</hi> (<hi rend="italic">what</hi>, we cannot here
          say) Education under the superintendence and direction of
          the state.</p>
                <p>When the sovereign is one, it is clear how he will and
          ought to direct the Education of his people. His first
          object must be to maintain the stability of his own power.
          It is an absurdity to suppose any Education permitted
          in any state which shall be inconsistent with the existence
          of that state; and consequently in a monarchy, the first
          object is and must be the preservation of the monarchy. It
          is unnecessary to show that the attainment of this object is
          by no means <hi rend="italic">inconsistent</hi> with good Education, and Education
          which is good when considered with reference to other
          objects than the conservation of the monarchy.
          In a democracy [DEMOCRACY] the business of the state is
          also plain and easy. It is not plain <hi rend="italic">how</hi> far and to <hi rend="italic">what</hi>
          classes of subjects the superintendence of the state should
          extend, for that may be as difficult to determine in a democracy
          as in any other form of government; but it is plain
          to what objects the superintendence of the state in such a
          community should extend. Its objects should be to maintain
          in all its purity the principle of individual political equality,
          that the sovereign power is in all and every person,
          that the will of the majority is the rule which all must
          obey, and that the expression of opinion on all subjects
          by speaking or writing, should be perfectly free. If any
          checks are wanting on the last head, they will always be
          supplied in a democracy by the positive morality of the
          society in a degree at least as great as is required, and
          certainly in a greater degree than in any other form of
          government.</p>
                <p>What must the state do in a political system which is neither
          a monarchy nor a democracy; in a system where there
          are contending elements, and none has yet obtained the
          superiority ? The answer is, it must do what it can, and that
          which it does, being the will of the stronger part for the time,
          must be considered right. But such a political system, though
          it may continue for a long time, is always moving (at least
          it is only safe when it is moving) in the direction impressed
          upon it by one or other of the contending powers which
          exist in the state. Still, so long as the struggle continues,
          there can be no Education in the sense which we are considering,
          no education which has the single, clear, and undivided
          object proposed to it in a monarchy and in a democracy.
          Such a political system then would appear to be
          wanting in one of the chief elements of a political system,
          which we have explained to be the bringing up of the
          citizens in such a manner as to secure the stability of that<pb n="2"/>system under which they live. In such a system as we here
          imagine, there being no <hi rend="italic">unity</hi> in the object, there can be
          no unity of means with reference to any object; and such a
          system might be more properly called an aggregation of
          political societies, than one political society; what is implied
          by the word aggregation being the existence of
          something just strong enough to keep the whole together.
          Such a society, in spite of its incongruity, may be kept together
          by several things: one may be, that the positive
          morality of the whole society is favourable to order, as
          characterized by a love of wealth, and impressed with a profound
          conviction of the necessity of leaving free to every
          individual the pursuit of wealth and the enjoyment of it
          when it is acquired. Another may be, that in this same
          society, though there are contending elements, there may
          be a slow and steady progress, and a gradual change,
          tending in one direction only: such a gradual progress in
          such a system may be regarded as the only security against
          its destruction.</p>
                <p>If the history of the world has ever presented, or if it now
          presents, such a phenomenon as we have attempted to
          escribe; further, if such a society contains the greatest
          known number of instances of enormous individual wealth
          opposed to the greatest amount of abject poverty; the
          highest intellectual cultivation and the greatest freedom of
          thought, side by side with the grossest ignorance and the
          darkest superstition; thousands in the enjoyment of wealth
          for which they never laboured, and tens of thousands depending
          for their daily bread upon the labour of their hands
          and the sensitive vibrations or the scale of commerce; political
          power in appearance widely diffused, in effect confined
          to the hands of a few; ignorance of the simplest
          elements of society in many of the rich and those who have
          power; ignorance not greater in those who are poor and
          have none - such a society, if it exists, is a society in which
          every reflecting man must at moments have misgivings as
          to its future condition and as to the happiness of those in
          whom he is most nearly interested. But if such a society
          contains a class, properly and truly denominated a middle
          class, a class neither enervated by excessive wealth and indolence
          nor depressed by poverty; a class that is characterized
          by industry and activity unexampled; a class that
          considers labour as the true source of happiness, and free
          inquiry on all subjects as the best privilege of a free man—
          such a society may exist and continue to be Indefinitely in
          a state of progressive improvement. Such a society, with
          its monstrous anomalies and defects, offers to a statesman
          of enlarged mind and vigorous understanding the strongest
          motive, while it supplies him with all the means, to give to
          the political system an impulse that shall carry it beyond the
          region of unstable equilibrium and place it at once in a
          state of security.</p>
                <p>In such a society the simple enunciation by one possessed
          of power, that Education is a part of the business of the
          state, would be considered as the forerunner of some
          measure wliich should lay the foundation of that unity
          without which the temporary prosperity of the nation can
          never become permanent and its real happiness can never
          be secured.</p>
                <p>The particular questions that the philosophic legislator
          has then to solve with respect to the education of the
          citizens, are - 1. How are teachers to be taught, and what
          are they to be taught? 2. How is the body of teachers
          to be directed, superintended, rewarded, and punished?
          3. What schools and what kinds of schools are to be established
          and encouraged for the Education of the people?
          4. What are the teachers to teach in those schools? 5. Where
          is the immediate government of such schools to be placed?
          6. And where the ultimate and supreme direction and
          control of such schools? The word Schools is here used
          as comprehending <hi rend="italic">all</hi> places of Education.</p>
                <p>It remains to consider those other relations of a man to the state in 
          which we view him as a producer of wealth for his own enjoyment Here 
          the general principle is, that the pursuit and enjoyment of wealth must 
          be left as free as the public interest requires; and this amount of freedom 
          will not depend in any great degree on the form of government. To this head, 
          that of the production of wealth, belong all the divisions of labour by 
          which a man, to use a homely but expressive phrase, gets his living, 
          or what in other words are called the professions, trades, and arts of a country. 
          The only way in which the state can with any advantage direct or 
          control the exercise of any profession, trade, or 
          art, is by requiring the person who undertakes to exercise 
          it to have been trained or educated for tbe purpose. Whether this should 
          be done in all cases, or in some and what cases, and to what extent and how, 
          are questions for a legislature guided by a philosopher to answer.</p>
                <p>In all countries called civilized this has been done to a certain extent. The legislation of our own country offers instances of great errors committed by legislating where no legislation was wanted, or by legislating badly. Perhaps instances may also be noted in all countries where evil has arisen for want of legislation on the subject. We may explain by example.</p>
                <p>Perhaps it is unnecessary for a state to require that a shoemaker, or a tailor, or a painter, or a sculptor, should be required to go through a certain course of training before he exercises his art. The best shoemaker and best tailor will be sure to find employment, and individual shoe¬makers and tailors have as ample means of giving instruction in their craft as can be desired. It may be true or not true, that tbe best painters and sculptors will meet with most employment; but is it unnecessary or is it necessary for a state to offer facilities and encouragement to those who design to educate themselves as painters and sculptors? Most civilized nations have decided this question by doing so, and there are many reasons in favour of such a policy.</p>
                <p>Ought the state to require the professor of law, of medicine, 
          or of religious teaching, to undergo some kind of preliminary Education, 
          and to obtain a certificate thereof? Nearly all civilized 
          countries have required the lawyer and physician to go 
          through some course of Education. There are strong reasons 
          in some countries, our own for instance, both for and 
          against such a requisition; but on the whole, 
          the reasons seem to preponderate in favour of 
          requiring such Education from him who designs to practise law, and still
          morefromhim who designs to practise the art o£ healing.
          Most civilized countries, perhaps all, except two (so far as
          we know), require <hi rend="italic">all</hi> persons who profess the teaching of
          religion to have received some Education, to be ascertained
          by some evidence. But in both the nations excepted, any
          person, however ignorant may preach on subjects which the
          mass of the community believe or affect to believe to be of
          eater importance both for their present and future welfare
          an any other subjects. Professing to maintain, as we hope
          they always will do, the principle of religiousfreedom,these
          two nations have fallen into the greatest inconsistencies. 
          They have checked the free expression of individual 
          opinion by word of mouth, and fettered it in the written 
          form, in the one country by the severe penalties of positive 
          law and the no less severe penalties of positive morality; 
          and in the other by the penalties of positive morality carried 
          to an excess which is destructive to the interests of the 
          society itself. (See Attorney-General v. Pearson, 3 Meri¬
          vale, 353.) But both nations allow any person, if he 
          professes to be a teacher of religion, however ignorant he 
          may be, to become the weekly, the daily instructor of thou¬
          sands, including children, who derive and have derived no 
          instruction of any kind except from this source. Such a 
          teaching or preaching, if it only assumes the name and 
          form of religious teaching, is permitted to inculcate prin¬
          ciples which may be subversive of the political system; and 
          it may and often does inculcate'principles the tendency of 
          which is to undermine the foundations ot all social order; 
          for it should never be forgotten that all religious teaching 
          must include moral teaching, though moral teaching is 
          quite distinct from religious teaching. And though it must 
          be admitted that no teacher of religion recommends a had 
          thing as bad, he may recommend a bad thing as good, 
          solely because he knows no better. We have endeavoured 
          to point out an anomaly which exists in certain political 
          institutions, and which can only be allowed to exist so 
          long as it protects itself under a specious and an honoured 
          but misunderstood name. For though it be admitted that 
          such anomaly exist it may be said that it cannot be 
          remedied without interfering with the important principle 
          of religious freedom. But what is religious or any other 
          freedom? Is it the individual power of doing or saying 
          what a man likes? Certainly not It means no more 
          than a freedom not inconsistent with the public welfare. 
          Still it may be urged that this is precisely the kind of free¬
          dom with which no state, where the principle of religious 
          freedom is admitted, can safely interfere. But this is only 
          bringing us round again to the question, What is religious 
          freedom ? To say that it cannot be interfered with is to<pb n="3"/>assume an 
          answer to the question. Does what is called religious freedom, 
          as the same is now understood, admitting it to produce much good, 
          produce also any evil? If it does, can the evil be remedied? 
          Is the free practice of any art or profession, medicine 
          or law, for instance, or the art of instructing children 
          in general knowledge, or perfect freedom in teaching and 
          expounding religious doctrines, inconsistent with the 
          condition of <hi rend="italic">qualification</hi>?<note>In discussing a subject of this kind in a limited space, it is not possible to anticipate objections 
            that may be fairly urged, or to state and answer them. For example, it may be said, if a 
            man ought not to preach without some evidence of qualification, why should a man print 
            a book on religious subjects without some evidence of qualification ? The answer is not difficult; 
            but we have not space to answer either this or numerous other objection that may be made.</note> How the <hi rend="italic">qualification</hi> is 
          to be ascertained, and what it is to be, is the question; 
          and it is a question which may be answered.</p>
                <p>In all that we have said on Education as a subject of legislation, it is assumed either that the state can enforce, if necessary, that which it enacts; or that the enactments of the state will be only the expression of the public will; or that they will be founded on reasons so clear and convincing as to receive, when promulgated, the assent and
        support of a majority large enough to secure their being carried into effect If some one of these conditions cannot be fulfilled, the legislation is premature, and will probably be injurious.</p>
                <p>The extent of that department of Education with which the 
          legislature should not interfere can only be fixed with 
          precision by ascertaining the extent of its proper, that 
          is, its useful interference. We may state, however, in 
          general terms, that the early and domestic Education of 
          the young of both sexes is in nearly all, perhaps all, 
          modern political systems, placed beyond the reach of 
          direct legislative control by the constitution of modern 
          society. But in as much as one of the great functions of 
          government is the instruction, direction, and superintendence 
          of the teaching body, even the domestic Education is 
          not beyond its influence, but will be subjected to it 
          in precisely the same degree as the state shall succeed 
          in forming a body of good teachers. For the importance 
          and value of Education (in some sense or other: it 
          matters not here in what sense) are universally admitted. 
          The objects of Education, it is true, are often 
          misunderstood by parents and those who have the charge 
          of youth, and the means are as often ill-calculated for 
          the end proposed. But this is only a consequence of 
          ignorance, not an indication that Education is undervalued. 
          When better objects and better means are proposed, 
          whether by individual example or by associations of 
          individuals called societies, or by the state, such 
          objects and means will be readily embraced by all 
          who can comprehend them. It being assumed that the 
          objects and means thus presented are desirable in 
          themselves, there can be no obstacle to the reception 
          of them, so far as the state allows the reception 
          to be voluntary, except the ignorance and prejudices 
          (which are, in fact, only ignorance under another name) 
          of those to whom they are proposed. But till this 
          obstacle which ignorance presents is overcome, nothing 
          can be effected in the way of improvement; and it being 
          admitted, that as to the department of education under 
          consideration, direct legislation is not the proper means, 
          some other means must be adopted. Individuals and societies 
          often effect their benevolent objects by example and by 
          the authority of their name and character. The state may 
          do the same. The influence of authority and example is 
          in all countries most efficient when the sovereign power 
          calls them in to its aid. Individuals may do much; 
          societies have done more; but Society (the whole, 
          in its collective power) is the body from which all 
          improvements must come that are calculated to operate on the mass. 
          From these considerations we conclude that if any state 
          seriously and anxiously apply itself to the business of 
          forming a body of teachers, it is impossible to foresee 
          how far the beneficial influence of such a body, well 
          organized, may extend. It may penetrate into the house 
          of the wealthy, where the child who is born to the 
          possession of wealth is not thereby secured in the 
          enjoyment of it or against any one calamity of human life. 
          His wealth may be wasted by improvidence; his health may 
          be enfeebled by indolence and debauchery; his understanding 
          maybe cramped and corrupted by vicious Education and bad example; 
          and he may become an object of detestation and contempt 
          though born to the command of wealth sufficient to purchase 
          all that society has to offer. This influence may also reach, 
          and perhaps sooner and more effectually reach, the hovels and 
          the garrets of the poor, where thousands of children are now 
          brought up under such circumstances, that to be unhealthy, 
          vicious, criminal, and unhappy, are the only results which, 
          as a general rule, can follow from the given conditions of 
          their existence. When the unhappy wretch, who cannot be 
          other than what he is, has at last transgressed the limits 
          of the positive morality of society, and got within the 
          verge of the penalties of the law, his crimes are blazoned 
          forth by thousands, the respectable part of society are 
          shocked at the disclosures, and are only relieved from 
          their pain when the criminal is hid in a prison, or his 
          life is taken by tbe executioner. But the example is soon 
          forgotten, and misery and vice fester in the very heart of society unheeded, till
          some new warning again startles it from its lethargy.</p>
                <p>It may appear almost superfluous to state that the true 
          interest of the sovereign power, considered in all its bearings, must coincide 
          with the interest of the governed; the difference in forms of government or in 
          the distribution of the sovereign power being mainly to be considered a difference 
          in the instruments or means by which an end is to be obtained. Nor is this 
          difference an unimportant one. Where the sovereign power is in all those 
          who as individuals are subject to it the coincidence of power and of interest is 
          complete; and the nearer any form of government approaches to this distribution 
          of power, the more obvious and the stronger is the principle laid down. 
          The principle may express a common-place truth; but the consequences that flow from it are 
          numerous and important. When it is clear that the state will promote the general good by its 
          regulations, its business is to make regulations. If regulations will not promote the general 
          good, that is a reason for not making them. Now to protect a man in the enjoyment of his 
          property, and to preserve him from the aggressions of others, is a main part of the business 
          of governing. For this purpose restraints and punishments are necessary; immediately, 
          to protect the injured, and give compensation, when it can be given; remotely, to prevent 
          others from being injured, and, so far as it can be done, to reform the offender. 
          But the punishment of any offender, in its extremest shape, can do little more than prevent 
          the same person from offending again. Those who are deterred from crime by his example can 
          at any rate only be those to whom the example is known, and they are a small portion even 
          of the actual society. Generally, then, those who do not offend against the laws, do not offend, 
          either because they have been sufficiently educated to avoid such offence, or because 
          the opportunity and temptation have not been presented to them, or because they know that 
          punishment may follow the crime. But a large class of offenders have not been sufficiently 
          educated to enable them to avoid the commission of crime; a very large number are brought up 
          amidst the opportunities, the temptations, and the example of crime, to oppose all which 
          the single fact of knowing that the crime <hi rend="italic">may</hi> be punished (and even that amount of knowledge 
          is not always possessed by the criminal) is all the means of resistance that such persons are armed with. 
          In societies which boast of their wealth, their civilization, and their high intellectual cultivation, 
          such is the feeble barrier opposed by those who have the government of a people between thousands of 
          their fellow-citizens and the commission of crimes the penalties of which are always severe and often cruel.</p>
                <p>If the general considerations which we have urged are of any weight, there is no branch 
          of legislation which comprehends so many important questions as are comprehended in the word Education, 
          even when taken in its ordinary acceptation; but when viewed in all its bearings, it is of all 
          questions most peculiarly that which it concerns the present age and the present state of society to determine. 
          That Education was an integral, an essential part of legislation, was clearly seen by the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Greeks">Greeks</name>, 
          to whom belongs the merit of having approached, and often having solved, nearly all the important 
          questions that affect the constitution of society. It was their good fortune to contemplate many truths 
          from a nearer poiut of view and in a clearer light than we can do now. The relations of modern society 
          are so numerous and complicated, that the mind is bewildered amidst the multiplicity and variety of facts, 
          the claims of opposing interests, and the number and magnitude of the objects which are presented 
          for its consideration. It is only by keeping ourselves as free as possible from mere party influences, 
          and steadily looking to the general welfare as the end to be attained by and the true test of ail political
          <pb n="4"/>institutions, that we can hope to discover and apply the 
          principles which shall secure, so far as such a thing can be secured, the universal happiness of a nation.</p>
                <p>
                    <quote>'That the legislator should especially occupy himself with the education of youth, no one can dispute; 
          for when this is not done in states, it is a cause of damage to the polity (form of government). 
          For a state must be administered with reference to its polity; and that which is the peculiar characteristic 
          of each polity is that which preserves and originally constitutes it; as, for instance, the democratical principle 
          in a democracy, and the oligarchal in an oligarchy; and that which is the best principle 
          always constitutes the best polity. Further, in every occupation and
          art a person must receive previous instruction and discipline, 
          in order to the exercising of the occupation or art; consequently also to the enabling him to the exercise of virtue. 
          Now, since the end of every state is one, it is evident that education must be <hi rend="italic">one</hi>, and of necessity the same for all, 
          and that the superintendence of the education must be with the public and not with individuals, 
          as it now is, when each individual superintends his own children singly, and teaches them what he chooses. 
          But when things are matter of public concern, the discipline pertaining to them must also be matter 
          of public concern; and we must not consider any citizen as belonging to himself, but 
          all as belonging to the state; for each is a part of the state, and the superintendence of 
          each part has naturally a reference to the superintendence of the whole. In the matter of 
          education, as well as in other matters, the <name type="people">Lacedemonians</name> deserve praise; for they take the 
          greatest pains about the education of their children, and that, too, as a public concern. 
          That then a state ought to legislate on education and make it a public concern, is clear;
          but what education is, and how education must be conducted, is a subject for consideration'</quote> (<name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aristotle">Aristotle</name>, <hi rend="italic">Politik</hi>, book viii.)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="entry" subtype="science">
                <head>
                    <term xml:id="Science">Science.</term>
                </head>
                <div type="article">
                    <p>SCIENCE. The word scientia, in real <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Latin">Latin</name>, simply
                    means knowledge, and we must attribute the subsequent
                    application of the word to particular kinds of knowledge, to
                    causes similar to those which have influenced the use of
                    the equally general term MATHEMATICS [vol. xv., p. 111.
                    It does not appear that in the earlier parts of the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Middle_Ages">middle
                    ages</name> science had any distinct meaning as opposed either to
                    literature or to art. Almost at the earliest establishment
                    of universities, the great preliminary branches of knowledge
                    were separated from the rest under the name of liberal
                    arts: that is to say, the Triviura, containing grammar,
                    logic, and rhetoric; and the Quadrivium, containing arithmetic,
                    geometry, astronomy, and music. If theology, law,
                    and medicine were called sciences, it was not in any distinctive
                    sense, and we are inclined to think that scientia
                    must then have been rather a term subaltern to art than
                    opposed to it. We find <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roger_Bacon">Roger Bacon</name>(Oj). Maj., cap. xv.)
                    speaking of the nine mathematical sciences, and the six
                    great natural sciences, which contain under them many
                    other sciences: and his contemporary <name type="person">Robert of Lincoln</name>
                    (Tract, de Art. Lib.), after laying it down that the arts (not
                    sciences), of which it is the office <q>'operationes hum anas
                    corrigendo ad perfectionem ducere,'</q> are seven in number,
                    proceeds to describe them without a single use of the word
                    science. How the word grew it is not our business to inquire
                    closely; but by the middle of the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/16th_century">sixteenth century</name>
                    the word science had begun to appear as denoting connected
                    and demonstrated knowledge, in opposition to art, which <pb n="1"/> signified digested rules of operation not connected with each
                    other by deduction from common first principles. Thus
                    <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Niccolò_Fontana_Tartaglia">Tartalea</name>, a writer on algebra (which was then, and most properly,
                    called only an art; ars magna, or arte moggiore),
                    styles <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Euclid">Euclid</name>, in the preface to his edition of the Elements,
                    <q>'the sole guide to the mathematical sciences.'</q> By the
                    middle of the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/17th_century">seventeenth century</name>, the term science was
                    freely used in the sense which it has never since lost,
                    namely, that in which it is opposed to literature. But the
                    old distinction of science as opposed to art has still remained,
                    though the two terms, in this sense, have been in great
                    measure superseded by theory and practice ; but improperly,
                    for the distinction between science and art is one thing,
                    and that between theory and practice another. [THEORY.]</p>
                    <p>A science, as distinguished from an art, is a body of
                    truths, the common principles of which are supposed to be
                    known and separated, so that the individual truths, even
                    though some or all may be clear in themselves, have a
                    guarantee that they could have been discovered and known,
                    either with certainty or with such probability as the subject
                    admits of, by other means than their own evidence. It
                    is not necessary that these truths should have been discovered
                    by a scientific process; it is enough that they admit
                    of such treatment subsequently. The telescope, for instance,
                    may have been discovered accidently; but it can now be
                    demonstrated beforehand that such an instrument must
                    produce the effect which it is known to produce, and the
                    rules for its construction may be deduced from the simple
                    fundamental properties of light. In the sense of the word
                    above used, the number of perfect sciences is not so great as
                    is commonly supposed; for many branches of knowledge
                    which bear the name are not perfect sciences, such as medicine,
                    zoology, and geology;—in all of these, large classifications
                    have been made, many principles have been deduced
                    which seem to be of universal application, and much has
                    been done to make these known principles point out the direction
                    of inquiry; but it would be idle to say that either
                    of them is a science in the sense in which astronomy is a
                    science.</p>
                    <p>Science, as opposed to literature, means any branch of
                    knowledge in which the affections of mind or matter are to
                    be made the subject of reasoning, with a view to discover
                    and apply first principles. The distinctions of mental and
                    physical sciences, the subdivision of the former into ethical
                    and psychological, &amp;c, whatever terms may be employed,
                    are real and useful. But as it is not the object here to
                    classify human knowledge, but only to give a slight account
                    of the mode of using a word, we may pass on to its common
                    signification.</p>
                    <p>By science, in popular language, is meant simply mathematical,
                    physical, or natural science, not with reference to
                    principles, but to results. Calculation, collection of natural
                    objects, construction of models, use of philosophical instruments,
                    any or either, is science, or part of science; and a
                    man of science (man of a science, or man of the art which
                    is built upon a science, would frequently be a correct
                    description) may be either a mathematician, mechanist,
                    engineer, medical practitioner, astronomer, geologist, electrician,
                    zoologist ornithologist &amp;c. To this sort of designation
                    there can be no objection in itself, and it is convenient
                    as distinguishing followers of science, or of a science, from
                    those of literature. But it is not sufficiently precise in itself
                    to distinguish the followers of different sciences from one
                    another. When a literary man is named, his pursuit is
                    generally indicated: the historian, the antiquary, the poet,
                    the novelist the politician, the scholar, and the linguist, are
                    not confounded by means of a general term: insomuch
                    that <q>'literary man,'</q> by itself, generally implies one of information,
                    but not of distinguished depth in any one
                    particular branch. But the inquirer into the sciences of
                    electricity and magnetism, for example, has no name to
                    distinguish him from the observer and classifier of insects;
                    that is to say, the proper technical names are not familiar
                    to the world at large. But this is the least inconvenience.
                    When the word science comes to be used in its high and
                    proper sense, indicative of truth discovered, error prevented,
                    inquiry organised, judicious habits formed, and mental
                    energy strengthened, it must be difficult for those who are
                    used to the common sense of the word to imagine the truth
                    of many things which are said about it. <q>'All we require is,
                    that he will hold his former opinions and judgments without
                    bigotry, retain till he shall see reason to question them,
                    be ready to resign them when fairly proved untenable, and to doubt them when the weight of probability is shown to
                    lie against them. If he refuse this, he is incapable of
                    science.'</q> Now this, though the word of a good authority,
                    and perfectly true, is nevertheless notoriously false in the
                    common sense of the word science: a man may be incapable
                    of the preceding state of mind, and may be a man
                    of science. There is no remedy for this confusion of terms,
                    except that which every one must make for himself, by
                    attention to the different senses of the word, the higher and
                    the lower.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>