<TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Putong baike xin dacidian 普通百科新大辭典 (A New Encyclopaedic Dictionary for Common Use)</title>
                <editor>Research Project "Hidden Grammars of Transculturality - Migrations of Encyclopedic Knowledge and Power"</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Project Coordination</resp>
                    <name xml:id="BM">Barbara Mittler</name>
                    <name xml:id="MH">Madeleine Herren-Oesch</name>
                    <name xml:id="JK">Joachim Kurtz</name>
                    <name xml:id="KMW">Kaja Mueller-Wang</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Technical supervision and file administration</resp>
                    <name xml:id="JP">Jens Østergaard Petersen</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>TEI header</resp>
                    <name xml:id="OS">Oliver Schulz</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cluster of Excellence "Asia and Europe in a Global Context"</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Heidelberg University</pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Karl Jaspers Centre for Advanced Transcultural Studies</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Voßstraße 2, Building 4400</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>69115 Heidelberg</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Germany</addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Putong baike xin dacidian 普通百科新大辭典 (A New Encyclopaedic Dictionary for Common Use)</title>
                        <author>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#HuangMoxi">Huang Moxi 黃摩西</name>
                        </author>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <edition>1st Edition</edition>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Zhongguo cidian gongsi 中國辭典公司 (Chinese dictionaries company)</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Shanghai 上海</pubPlace>
                        <date>Xuantong xinhai (1911)</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>Other editions: At least three reprints.</note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <settlement>Heidelberg University</settlement>
                        <repository>Library of the Institute of Chinese Studies</repository>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>
                        <p>Size: 11.72 in (29,77 cm) * 8.25 in (20.96 cm) </p>
                        <p>Volumes: 15 ce</p>
                        <p>Script: Print</p>
                        <p>Illustrations: It includes graphic representations for illustrating certain entries.</p>
                    </physDesc>
                    <msPart>
                        <altIdentifier>
                            <idno/>
                        </altIdentifier>
                        <msContents>
                            <p>Lemma-organization: Ordered by stroke count.</p>
                            <p>Table of contents: None.</p>
                            <p>Index: Two kinds. a) Fenlei mulu, entries firstly grouped by its category and then by stroke count. Shows the page number below.
                               b) Index with other names. If an entry is known under an other name, it might be shown here.</p>
                            <p>Contents: Covers a broad thematic range, sciences and humanities, but also very practical themes are included.<lb/> </p>
                        </msContents>
                        <history>
                            <p>A copy and a scan of the work is available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <settingDesc>
                <p>The book was compiled and written by Huang Moxi, with some assistance by other scholars. The project was supported by the Society for the Preservation of National Learning.</p>
                <p>The Chinese dictionaries company was a private institution, founded in 1902, had its greatest concentration of publishing activities between 1909-1915, primarily putted out materials to Chinese culture.</p>
            </settingDesc>
            <textDesc>
                <channel mode="w">print</channel>
                <constitution type="single">A text divided into many short entries.</constitution>
                <derivation type="abridgment">Huang probably wrote a lot by himself, but has also copied and translated entries from other dicitionaries.</derivation>
                <domain type="education"/>
                <factuality type="fact"></factuality>
                <interaction type="none" active="singular" passive="world"/>
                <preparedness type="none"/>
                <purpose type="inform" degree="high"/>
                <purpose type="entertain" degree="low"/>
                <purpose>Huang Ren shared admiration for the scholarly achievements of the West, but was deeply rooted in Chinese culture as well. With this book he wants to show that the West is an object worth studying.</purpose>
            </textDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="zh" usage="97">Chinese</language>
                <language ident="en" usage="03"></language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Scans available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
            <p>Digitalization by Formax BPO Beijing Inc., special instructions for typing Chinese texts and encyclopedias developed by
                Wolfgang Schmidle et. al. at Max Planck Institute for the History of Science, Berlin. 
                Transformation of the digitized raw texts into TEI done by Wolfgang Schmidle. 
                TEI Header and mark-ups inserted by project members at Heidelberg University.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-08-23" who="#OS">created</change>
            <change when="2011-08-25" who="#OS">Questionnaire info added to TEI header</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="entry"/>                            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

