<TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Riyong baike quanshu bubian 日用百科全書補編 (Addendum to the Everyday Cyclopedia)</title>
                <editor>Research Project "Hidden Grammars of Transculturality - Migrations of Encyclopedic Knowledge and Power"</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Project Coordination</resp>
                    <name xml:id="BM">Barbara Mittler</name>
                    <name xml:id="MH">Madeleine Herren-Oesch</name>
                    <name xml:id="JK">Joachim Kurtz</name>
                    <name xml:id="KMW">Kaja Mueller-Wang</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Technical supervision and file administration</resp>
                    <name xml:id="JP">Jens Østergaard Petersen</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>TEI header</resp>
                    <name xml:id="OS">Oliver Schulz</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cluster of Excellence "Asia and Europe in a Global Context"</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Heidelberg University</pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Karl Jaspers Centre for Advanced Transcultural Studies</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Voßstraße 2, Building 4400</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>69115 Heidelberg</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Germany</addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Riyong baike quanshu 日用百科全書補編 (Addendum to the Everyday Cyclopedia)</title>
                        <author>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#HeSongling">He Songling 何崧齡</name>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#TangJinggao">Tang Jinggao 唐敬杲</name>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#WangXiulu">Wang Xiulu 王岫盧</name>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#HuJunfu">Hu Junfu 胡君復</name>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#RuanXiang">Ruan Xiang 阮湘</name>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#XuShouling">Xu Shouling</name>
                        </author>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <edition>1st Edition</edition>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Shanghai yinshuguan 上海印書館 (Commercial Press)</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Shanghai 上海</pubPlace>
                        <date>[1925]</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>Other editions: The addendum went through several reprints.</note>
                        <note>Connected editions: The Everyday Cyclopedia日用百科全書 (1919), The Newly Compiled Everyday Cyclopedia 重編日用百科全書 (1934). </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <settlement>Heidelberg University</settlement>
                        <repository>Library of the Institute of Chinese Studies</repository>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>
                        <p>Size: 11.72 in (29,77 cm) * 8.25 in (20.96 cm) </p>
                        <p>Volumes: 1 juan</p>
                        <p>Script: Print</p>
                        <p>Illustrations: many tables and drawings</p>
                    </physDesc>
                    <msPart>
                        <altIdentifier>
                            <idno/>
                        </altIdentifier>
                        <msContents>
                            <p>Lemma-organization: 43 topics.</p>
                            <p>Table of contents: a division of the 43 topics, which are further subdivided, listed in the beginning of the book. The old category “Magical calculation”術數 was completely left out.</p>
                            <p>Index: none.</p>
                            <p>Contents: The addendum adds new facts and materials to the original version. It also views topics from another perspective, f.e. for history in a more international way. Although most of the categories are the same, the content in general is, as the name says, an addendum. </p>
                        </msContents>
                        <history>
                            <p>A scan of the work is available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
           <settingDesc>
                <p>There were many editors, whereby He Songling functioned as the chief editor.</p>
                <p>The Shanghai yinshuguan (Commercial Press) hired many translators, who were often studying in Europe or the USA. Some of the editors of this cyclopedia possibly did have such a background.</p>  
                <p>Compared to the original edition the editors changed in total.</p>
                <p>The publisher Shanghai yinshuguan was founded in 1897. 
                   Shanghai yinshuguan later became a very influential press, publishing primary and secondary education textbooks, dictionaries, as well as important magazines: 
                   "Eastern Miscellany" (東方雜誌), "Education Magazine" (教育雜誌), "The Short Story Magazine" (小說月報), "Youth Magazine" (少年雜誌), "Students' Magazine" (學生雜誌). The publishing house acted without government support, its publishing strategy was market-oriented.</p>
            </settingDesc>
            <textDesc>
                <channel mode="w">print</channel>
                <constitution type="single">A complete text, ordered into 43 categories, which are written in an essayist form.
                    The entries are smaller than the original, as it only adds facts the cyclopedia published six years before. Every entry is separately paginated.
                </constitution>
                <derivation type="abridgment">It might draw on different kinds of sources from Western and Chinese origin as did the original.</derivation>
                <domain type="education"/>
                <factuality type="fact"></factuality>
                <interaction type="none" active="singular" passive="world"/>
                <preparedness type="spontaneous"/>
                <purpose type="inform" degree="high"/>
                <purpose type="entertain" degree="low"/>
                <purpose>The book was intended to inform and educate the common citizen of the new Chinese nation and creates an indispensable general knowledge. Includes many practical devices and often reads more like a user manual. </purpose>
            </textDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="zh" usage="99">Chinese</language>
                <language ident="en" usage="01"></language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Scans available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
            <p>Digitalization by Formax BPO Beijing Inc., special instructions for typing Chinese texts and encyclopedias developed by
               Wolfgang Schmidle et. al. at Max Planck Institute for the History of Science, Berlin. 
               Transformation of the digitized raw texts into TEI done by Wolfgang Schmidle. 
               TEI Header and mark-ups inserted by project members at Heidelberg University.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-08-23" who="#OS">created</change>
            <change when="2011-08-23" who="#OS">Questionnaire info added to TEI header</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
       <body>
            <div type="entry" subtype="education"/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>