<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The Standard Library Cyclopedia of Political, Constitutional, Statistical and
          Forensic Knowledge Vol.II</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>London: Henri G. Bohn, York Street, Covent Garden. 1848.</p>
                <p>Vol II of VI, Full Title The Standard Cyclopedia of Political, Constitutional,
          Statistical and Forensic Knowledge: Forming a Work of Universal Reference on the Subjects
          of Civil Administration, Political Economy, Finance, Commerce, Laws and Social Relations.
          Translated in to Japanese in "taisei seiji ruiten" (Reynold, Douglas R.:"Japanese
          Encyclopaedias: Their Backround and Hidden Impact on Late-Qing Chinese Encyclopaedias",
          Georgia State University, in: Doleželová-Velingerová, Milena and Wagner, Rudolf G.(Eds.):
          "Chinese Encyclopaedias of New Global Knowledge (1870-1920) p. 169)</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Google Books</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb n="512"/>
            <div type="entry">
                <head>
                    <term xml:id="City">City</term>
                </head>
                <div type="article">
                    <p>CITY (in <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/French_language">French</name>
                        <hi rend="italic">Cité</hi>, ultimately from the Latin <hi rend="italic">Civitas</hi>).
            Certain large and ancient towns both in <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England">England</name> and in other countries are
            called cities, and they are supposed to rank before other towns. On what the distinction
            is founded is not well ascertained. The word seems to be one of common use, or at most
            to be used in the letters and charters of kings as a complimentary or honorary name,
            rather than as betokening the possession of any social privileges which may not and in
            fact do not belong to other ancient and incorpo-<pb n="513"/>rated places which are
            still known only by the name of towns or boroughs. <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/César-Pierre_Richelet">Richelet</name> (<hi rend="italic">Dictionnaire</hi>) says that the French word <hi rend="italic">cité</hi>
            is only used in general when we speak of places where there are two towns, an old town
            and another which has been built since; and he adds that <q>"la cité de <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paris">Paris</name>"</q> means old
              <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paris">Paris</name>.</p>
                    <p>
                        <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Blackstone">Sir William
              Blackstone</name>, following <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_Coke">Coke</name> (1 <hi rend="italic">Inst.</hi> 109 b), says, <q>" A city is a town incorporated, which is or hath been
              the see of a bishop."</q> (<hi rend="italic">Comm. Introd</hi>., sec. iv.) But <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/City_of_Westminster">Westminster</name>
            is a city, though it is not incorporated, <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thetford">Thetford</name> is a town, though
            incorporated, and once the seat of a bishop. Whether Westminster owes its designation to
            the circumstance that it had a bishop for a few years of the reign of <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VIII_of_England">Henry
              VIII.</name>, and in the reign of <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_VI_of_England">Edward VI.</name>, may be
            doubted. But there are, besides Thetford, many places which were once the seats of
            bishops, as <name type="place">Sherburn</name>, and <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dorchester,_Oxfordshire">Dorchester</name> in <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Oxfordshire">Oxfordshire</name>, which
            are never called cities. On the whole, we can rather say that certain of our ancient
            towns are called cities, and their inhabitants citizens, than show why this distinction
            prevails and what are the criteria by which they are distinguished from other towns.
            These ancient towns are those in which the cathedral of a bishop is found; to which are
            to be added <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bath,_Somerset">Bath</name> and <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Coventry">Coventry</name>, which, respectively with <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Wells">Wells</name> and <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lichfield">Lichfield</name>, occur in the designation
            of the bishop in whose diocese they are situated; and Westminster, which in this respect
            stands alone.</p>
                    <p>In the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States">United States
              of North America</name> the name City is usually given to large towns, as <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_City">New York</name>, <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philadelphia">Philadelphia</name>, and
            others.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="516"/>
            <div type="entry">
                <head>
                    <term xml:id="Civilization">Civilization</term>
                </head>
                <div type="article">
                    <p>CIVILIZATION. The words civilization, education, and religion, with many others, are
            often used without any precise ideas being attached to them; yet there are no words that
            require to be more thoroughly analysed.</p>
                    <p>The meaning of a word is often formed by degrees. As soon as a particular fact presents
            itself to our notice which appears to have a specific relation to a known term, it
            becomes immediately incorporated with it; and hence the meaning of many terms gradually
            extends, and finally embraces all the various facts and ideas which are considered to
            belong to it. On this account, there is more depth as well as accuracy in the usual and
            ordinary meaning of complex terms than in any definitions which can be given of them,
            notwithstanding the definition may appear to be more strict and precise. In the majority
            of instances scientific definitions are too narrow, and owing to this circumstance they
            are frequently less exact than the popular meaning of terms; it is therefore in its
            popular and ordinary signification that we must seek for the various ideas that are
            included in the term civilization.</p>
                    <p>Now, the fundamental notion of civilization is that of a progressive movement, of a
            gradual development, and a tendency to amelioration. It always suggests the idea of a
            community, of a political body, of a nation, which is advancing methodically, and with
            distinct and clear views of the objects which it seeks to attain: progress, continual
            improvement, is therefore the fundamental idea contained in our notion of the term
            Civilization.</p>
                    <p>As to this progress and improvement involved in the term Civilization, to what do they
            apply ? The etymology of the word answers the question. From this we learn that it does
            not contemplate the actual number, power, or wealth of a people, but their <hi rend="italic">civil</hi> condition, their social relations, and intercourse with each
            other. Such then is the first impression which arises in our mind when we pronounce the
            word <hi rend="italic">Civilization</hi>. It seems to represent to us at once the
            greatest activity and the best possible organization of society; so as to be productive
            of a continual increase, and a distribution of wealth and power among its members,
            whereby their absolute and relative condition is kept in a state of constant
            improvement.</p>
                    <p>But great as is the influence which a well organised civil society must have upon the
            happiness of the human race, the term Civilization seems to convey something still more
            extensive, more foil and complete, and of a more elevated and dignified character, than
            the mere perfection of the social relations, as a matter of order and arrangement. In
            this other aspect of the word it embraces the development of the intellectual and moral
            faculties of man, of his feelings, his propensities, his natural capacities, and his
            tastes.</p>
                    <p>Education, which is the result of a well ordered social arrangement and also its
            perfector and conservator, an education which shall give to every member of the
            community the best opportunities for developing the whole of his faculties, is the end
            which civilisation, or a society in a state of continued progress, must always have in
            view.</p>
                    <p>The fundamental ideas then, contained<pb n="516"/>in the word Civilization are—the
            continual advancement of the whole society in wealth and prosperity, and the improvement
            of man in his individual capacity.</p>
                    <p>When the one proceeds without the other, it is immediately felt that there is something
            incomplete and wanting. The mere increase of national wealth, unaccompanied by a
            corresponding knowledge and intelligence on the part of the people, seems to he a state
            of things premature in existence, uncertain in duration, and insecure as to its
            stability. We are unacquainted with the causes of its origin, the principles to which it
            can be traced, and what hopes we may form of its continuance. We wish to persuade
            ourselves that this prosperity will not be limited to a few generations, or to a
            particular people or country, but that it will gradually spread, and finally become the
            inheritance of all the people of the earth. And yet what rational expectation can we
            entertain of such a state of things becoming universal? It is only by means of
            education, conducted upon right principles, that we can ever nope to see true national
            prosperity attained, and rendered permanent The development of the moral and
            intellectual faculties must go hand in hand with the cultivation of the industrious
            arts; united, they form the great engine for giving true civilization to the world.</p>
                    <p>In fact without the union of these two elements, civilization would stop half way; mere
            external advantages are liable to be lost or abused without the aid of those more
            refined and exalted studies which tend to improve the mind, and call forth the feelings
            and affections of the heart It must be repeated, civilization consists in the
            progressive improvement of the society considered as a whole, and of all the individual
            members of which it is composed.</p>
                    <p>The means by which this improvement of the whole of a society and of all the members of
            it may be best effected, will vary somewhat in different countries. <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Europe">European</name> nations consider and call
            their social state civilized, and they view the social states of other countries, which
            do not rest on the same foundation, either as barbarous or as less civilized than their
            own. An impartial observer may allow that if we measure civilization by the rule here
            laid down, <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Europe">the nations of
              Europe</name>, and other nations whose social systems have a like basis, are the most
            civilized. The civilization of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Europe">Europe</name> and of the nations of European
            origin is founded mainly on two elements, the Christian religion and the social state
            which grew up from the diffusion of the power of the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ancient_Rome">Romans</name>. The establishment of
            feudality in many countries greatly affected the social basis; and the consequences are
            still seen, but more distinctly in some parts of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Europe">Europe</name> than in others. The elements of
            such a social system are essentially different from those on which is founded the system
            of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/China">China</name>, of the
            nations which profess Mohammedanism, and of the nations of the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/India">Indian peninsula</name>. European civilization
            is active and restless, but still subordinate to constituted authority. It gives to man
            the desire and the means to acquire wealth at home, and it stimulates him to adventure
            and discovery abroad. It seeks to assimilate the civilization of other nations to its
            own by conquest and colonization, and it is intolerant of all civilization that is
            opposed to itself. <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Asia">Asiatic</name> civilization is at present inert, it is not in a state of progress,
            and is exposed to the inroads of European civilization. European civilization has been
            and is most active in increasing the power of states as states, and in increasing their
            wealth; it also gives facilities for men of talent and enterprise to acquire wealth and
            power by means recognised as legal and just; and it is now beginning to extend the means
            of individual improvement among all the members of its communities more widely than any
            other civilization; but the amount of poverty and ignorance which still co-exist by the
            side ox wealth and intelligence, wherever European civilization has been established,
            show that much remains to be done before the individual happiness of these States can be
            as complete and their internal condition as sound as their collective wealth is
            unbounded and their external aspect is fair and flourishing.</p>
                    <p>The nations of Europe consider their<pb n="517"/>social system as the standard by which
            the civilization of other countries must be measured, and they assume as a fundamental
            principle, that in countries where there is no individual property in land, and where
            the land is not cultivated, there is no civilization, and that they may therefore seise
            it This assumption is true, if we measure civilization by the rule here laid down, for
            on individual ownership of land, and the cultivation of land, the whole European system
            rests. Whether land might be advantageously cultivated in common, and the institution of
            private property in land might be abolished, is another question, which however has not
            yet been satisfactorily resolved, end cannot be resolved without destroying the present
            social systems of Europe.</p>
                    <p>A recent committee of the <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/House_of_Commons_of_the_United_Kingdom">House of
              Commons</name>, appointed to inquire into the state of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_Zealand">New Zealand</name>, have put forth the
            following doctrine :—<q>"The uncivilized inhabitants of any country have but a qualified
              dominion over it, or a right of occupancy only, and until they establish amongst
              themselves a settled form of government and subjugate the ground to their own uses by
              the cultivation of it they cannot grant to individuals, not of their own tribe, any
              portion of it for the simple reason that they have not themselves any individual
              property in it."</q> This is not very precise language, but one may collect what it
            means. <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Earl_of_Derby">Lord
              Stanley</name>, in a despatch to the governor of New Zealand, dated 13th August, 1844,
            says, <q>"With respect to this doctrine, I am not sure that, were the question one of
              mere theory, I should be prepared to subscribe, unhesitatingly and without reserve, to
              the fundamental assumption of the committee; and I am sure that it would require
              considerable qualification as applicable to the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Māori">aborigines of New Zealand</name>. There are
              many gradations of 'uncivilized inhabitants,' and practically according to their state
              of civilization mustt be the extent of the rights which they can be allowed to claim,
              whenever the territory on which they reside is occupied by civilized communities."</q>
            After describing the <q>"<name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Indigenous_Australians">aborigines of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_Holland_(Australia)">New
                  Holland</name>
                            </name>"</q> as far below <q>"the <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Māori">New Zealanders</name> in civilization, and
              being wholly ignorant of or averse to the cultivation of the soil, with no principles
              of civil government or recognition of private property, and little if any knowledge of
              the simplestst form of religion, or even of the existence of a Supreme being;"</q> he
            adds, that <q>"it is impossible to admit on the part of a population thus situated, any
              rights in the soil which should be permitted to interfere with the subjugation by
                <name type="people" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ethnic_groups_in_Europe">Europeans</name> of the vast wilderness over which they are scattered; and all that
              can be required by justice, sanctioned by policy;, or recommended by humanity, is to
              endeavour, as civilization and cultivation extend, to embrace the aborigines within
              their pale, to diffuse religious knowledge among them, to induce them, if possible, to
              adopt more settled means of providing for their subsistence, and to afford them the
              means of doing so, if so disposed, by an adequate reservation of lands within the
              limits of cultivation."</q> The principles laid down by <name type="person" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Earl_of_Derby">Lord Stanley</name> are those which
            the civilized nations of Europe have long acted on, sometimes tempering their conquests
            of uncivilized nations with mercy and humanity, and sometimes treating them as if they
            were merely wild beasts that infested the country. The foundations on which even Lord
            Stanley places the justification of European occupation are not stated with much
            precision. The real foundations are, the enterprising spirit of Europeans; the pressure
            of difficulties at home, which drive men abroad; the necessity of possessing land in
            their new country, as the basis ot that edifice of civilization which they propose to
            erect after the model of the mother country ; and the power to take from those who are
            too feeble to resist Europeans admit, and the admission is contained by implication in
            Lord Stanley's remarks, that the nearer a nation's social system approaches to their
            own, the safer should it be against unprovoked aggression; but they contend, as Lord
            Stanley does, that the same self-restraint will not and ought not to be practised in
            those cases where the social system, or the mode of life, is altogether opposed to those
            fundamental principles on which European society is constituted. </p>
                    <pb n="516"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            <pb n="809"/>
            <div type="entry">
                <head>
                    <term xml:id="Education">Education</term>
                </head>
                <div type="article">
                    <p>EDUCATION. In every nation, even those called uncivilized, there are, and necessarily
            must be, certain practices and usages according to which children are instructed in
            those things which are to form the occupation of their future life; and every civilized
            nation, and, we may presume, nations also called uncivilized, have some general term by
            which they express this process of instruction. In the <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Languages_of_Europe">European languages</name>
            derived from the <name type="language" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Latin">Latin</name>, and in others that have a mixture of that language, this general term
            is Education. It is not important to consider the more or less precise notions attached
            to this or any other equivalent word, but it is enough to observe, that, as the language
            of every nation possesses such a term, it is a universal truth that all nations admit
            that there is something which is expressed by the comprehensive term education; or by
            some equivalent term. But like all other general terms which have been long in use, this
            term Education comprehends within the general meaning already assigned to it a great
            number of particulars, which are conceived by various people in such different modes and
            degrees and in such varying amount as to the number of the particulars, some nations or
            individuals conceiving a certain set of particulars as essential to the term, others
            conceiving a different set of particulars as essentials, and others again conceiving the
            same particulars in such different ways, that two or more persons who agree in their
            general description of the term might very probably, in descending into the enumeration
            of the particulars, find themselves completely at variance with one another. This remark
            possesses no claim to novelty, but it is not on that account the less important The
            discrepancy just stated is apparent not only as to such general terms as Education,
            Government, Right, Duty, and numerous other such words; but it is perceived and occurs
            even in things obvious to the senses, which consist of a number of parts, such as a
            machine, or any other compound thing;. The general use of a machine, as a mill, for
            instance, is conceived in the same wav by all, by the miller and by persons who knew
            nothing more about the mill than that it is used for grinding corn. As to the
            particulars, there may be all imaginable discrepancies among the persons who are only
            acquainted with the general purpose of the mill. But discrepancies as to the mode in
            which the several parts of a thing and the uses of the several parts are conceived, are
            generally discrepancies to be referred to the inaccuracy of the conceptions; they are,
            in fact, only errors, not the same but about the same thing. The more completely a large
            number of persons approach to harmony in their whole views as to this machine, the
            nearer, as a general rule, do their several views, approach to accuracy; it being of the
            nature of truth to produce a harmony of opinion, the truth being one and invariable; and
            it being of the nature of error<pb n="809"/>to admit of more varieties than man has yet
            conceived, inasmuch as men yet unborn will conceive errors never conceived before.</p>
                    <p>The same holds good as to Education which holds good of the machine. The general use,
            the general object of Education is roughly and rightly conceived by all persons to whom
            the name is familiar; but the great contrariety which exists among mankind as to the
            particulars which they conceive as entering into and forming a part of this term, and as
            to their mode of conceiving the same, proves either that all are still wrong as to their
            particular conceptions of this term, or that hitherto no means have been discovered of
            producing a general harmony of opinion, or in other words, of approaching to the truth.
            And here there is no person, or class of persons, who, as in the case of the miller, is
            or are allowed to be an authority competent to decide between conflicting opinions.</p>
                    <p>In every society, Education (in what particular manner conceived by any particular
            society is of no importance to our present inquiry) is, as a general rule, and must
            necessarily be, subjected to the positive law of the society, and to that assemblage of
            opinions, customs and habits which is not inappropriately called by some writers the
            Positive Morality of Society, or the Law of Opinion. This truth, or truism, as some may
            call it, is the basis of every inquiry into Education. In no country can there exist, as
            a general rule, an Education, whether it be good or bad, not subordinate to the law as
            above explained: for if such Education did exist, the form of that society or political
            system could not coexist with it. One or the other must be changed, so that on the whole
            there must at last result a harmony, and not a discord. In every country then there does
            exist Education, either directed by and subordinate to the Positive Law and Positive
            Morality of that country, or there is an Education not so directed and subordinate, and
            consequently inconsistent with the continuance of that political system in which it
            exists. But such an anomaly, if found anywhere, should not be allowed to exist, because
            it is inconsistent with the continued existence of the society in which it has
            established itself; and if such an Education does exist, and can maintain itself in a
            society, against the will of that society, such a society is not a sovereign and
            independent society, but is in a state of anarchy. Education then should be in harmony
            with and subordinate to the political system: it should be part of it; and whether the
            political system is called by the name good or bad, if that political system is to
            continue, Education must not be opposed to it, but must be a part of it. From this it
            follows that the question, What is the best education? involves the question, What is
            the best political system? and that question again cannot be answered without
            considering what are the circumstances of the particular nation or society as to which
            we inquire what is the best political system. Recollecting however that the question of
            the best education and of the best political system cannot be discussed apart, because,
            as we have shown, Education is a part of the system, still we can consider several
            important questions as to Education, without determining what is the best political
            system.</p>
                    <p>One is, the political system being given, what ought the Education to be? And, how far
            is it the business of the state to direct, control, and encourage that Education?</p>
                    <p>A man (under which term we include woman) has two distinct relations or classes of
            relations towards the state: one comprehends his duties as a citizen, wherein he is or
            ought to be wholly subordinate to the state; the other comprehends all his functions as
            a producer and enjoyer of wealth, wherein he has or ought to have all freedom that is
            not inconsistent with the proper discharge of his duties as a citizen. It is barely
            necessary to state this proposition in order to perceive that his Education as a citizen
            should be directed by the state. To suppose any other directing power, any power for
            instance which may educate im in principles opposed to the polity of which he is to form
            a part, is to suppose an inconsistency which, in discussing any question involving
            principles, we always intend to avoid.</p>
                    <pb n="810"/>
                    <p>His Education then as a citizen, it must be admitted, ought to be under the
            superintendence of the state: but How ought the state to exercise this
            superintendence?</p>
                    <p>It is not our purpose to attempt to answer this question, which involves the
            consideration of some of the most difficult questions in legislation. It is our object
            here to present the questions which it belongs to the civilization of the present and
            future ages to solve; to show What is to be done, not How it is to be done. But we may
            answer the question so far at this: the state having the superintendence of the
            citizen's Education, must have the superintendence of those who direct that Education;
            in other words, must direct those who are to carry its purposes into effect The body of
            teachers therefore must be formed by, or, at least, must be under the superintendence of
            the state. Unless this fundamental truth is admitted and acted on, the state cannot
            effectually direct or superintend the Education of its citizens.</p>
                    <p>Every branch of this inquiry into Education runs out into other branches almost
            Innumerable, till we find that the solution of this important question involves the
            solution of the greater part of those questions which occupy or ought to occupy a
            legislative body. For this reason, as above stated, we cannot attempt to answer in its
            full extent, How the state must direct the Education of its citizens, because this
            question involves the consideration of How far the direction and control of the state
            should be a matter of positive law imperative on all, how far and with respect to what
            particular matters it should encourage and give facilities only, how far it should act
            by penalties or punishment, how far it should allow individuals or associations of
            individuals to teach or direct teaching according to their own will and judgment, or, to
            express the last question in other words, whether and to what extent the state should
            allow competition in Education?</p>
                    <p>To these questions, and more especially to the last, the answer is in general terms,
            that the general interest, considered in all its bearings, must determine what and how
            much the state must do. This answer may be said to determine nothing. It is true it
            determines no particular thing, but it determines the principle by which all particular
            measures must be tested; and it would not be difficult to select instances from our own
            legislation, where enactments relating to places of education have been made with a view
            to particular interests only, without a reference to all the bearings of the question,
            and which, consequently, if tried by the test above given, would be found to be
            mischievous. As to the last question, the answer more particularly is,—that individual
            competition must not be destroyed. It is possible to reconcile the two principles of
            state direction and control and individual competition. The state may allow no person to
            teach without being examined and registered: such register will show if he has been
            trained under the superintendence of the state or not This fact being established, it
            may be left to individuals or associations of individuals to employ what teachers they
            please. In all the schools founded by the state, in all schools under the
            superintendence of the state (to which latter class belong nearly all charitable
            foundations; and all such foundations which are not under the superintendence of the
            state ought, consistently with the general principles already laid down, to be brought
            under that superintendence), it follows as a matter of course that none but teachers
            trained under the superintendence of the state should be appointed. The selection of the
            teachers, out of the whole authorized body, for any particular school of the class just
            described, may be safely left to the local authorities who have the immediate
            superintendence of these schools.</p>
                    <p>If the principle that a state ought to exercise a superintendence over the Education of
            its citizens as citizens be admitted, it may be asked, how far and to what branches of
            knowledge does this extend? To this we reply that a precise answer can only be given by
            the legislature of each country, and the question cannot be answered without many years
            of labour and perhaps without many experiments. But it follows from the principles<pb n="811"/>already laid down that no citizen ought to exercise any function of
            government, or be intrusted with the exercise of any power delegated by the state,
            without having received some (what, we cannot here say) Education under the
            superintendence and direction of the state.</p>
                    <p>When the sovereign is one, it is clear how he will and ought to direct the Education of
            his people. His first object must be to maintain his own power. It is an absurdity to
            suppose any Education permitted in any state which shall be inconsistent with tbe
            existence of that state; and consequently in a monarchy, the first object is and must be
            the preservation of the <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Monarchy">monarchy</name>. It is unnecessary to show
            that the attainment of this object is by no means inconsistent with good Education, and
            Education which is good when considered with reference to other objects than the
            conservation of the monarchy.</p>
                    <p>In a <name type="institution" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Democracy">democracy</name> [DEMOCRACY] tbe business of the state is also plain and easy. It is
            not plain how far and to what classes of subjects the superintendence of the state
            should extend, for that may be as difficult to determine in a democracy as in any other
            form of government; but it is plain to what objects the superintendence of the state in
            such a community should extend. Its objects should be to maintain in all its purity the
            principle of individual political equality, that the sovereign power is in all and every
            person, that the will of the majority declared in the form prescribed by the
            constitution, is the rule which all must obey, and that the expression of opinion on all
            subjects, by speaking or writing, should be perfectly free. If any checks are wanting on
            the last head, they will always be supplied in a democracy by the positive morality of
            the society in a degree at least great as is required, and certainly in a greater degree
            than in any other form of government; and when opinion is ineffectual, law must supply
            its weakness.</p>
                    <p>What must the state do in a political system which is neither a monarchy nor a
            democracy; in a system where there are contending elements, and none has yet obtained
            the superiority? The answer is, it must do what it can, and that which it does, being
            the will of the stronger part for the time, must be considered right. But such a
            political system, though it may continue for a long time, is always moving (at least it
            is only safe when it is moving) in the direction impressed upon it by one or other of
            the contending powers which exist in the state. Still, so long as the struggle
            continues, there can be no Education in the sense which we are considering, no Education
            which has the single, clear, and undivided object proposed to it in a monarchy and in a
            democracy. Such a political system then would appear to be wanting in one of the chief
            elements of a political system, which we have explained to be the bringing up of the
            citizens in such a manner as to secure the stability of that system under which they
            live. In such a system as we here imagine, there being no unity in the object, there can
            be no unity of means with reference to any object; and such a system might be more
            properly called an aggregation of political societies, than one political society; what
            is implied by the word aggregation being the existence of something just strong enough
            to keep the whole together. Such a society, in spite of its incongruity, may be kept
            together by several things: one may be, that the positive morality of the whole society
            is favourable to order, as characterized by a love of wealth, and impressed with a
            profound conviction of the necessity of leaving free to every individual the pursuit of
            wealth and the enjoyment of it when it is acquired. Another may be, that in this same
            society, though there are contending elements, there may be a slow and steady progress,
            and a gradual change, tending in one direction only; such a gradual progress in such a
            system may be regarded as the only security against its destruction.</p>
                    <p>If the history of the world has ever presented, or if it now presents, such a
            phenomenon as we have attempted to describe; further, if such a society contains the
            greatest known number of instances of enormous individual wealth opposed to the greatest
            amount of abject poverty; the highest intellectual cultivation and the greatest freedom
            of thought, side by<pb n="812"/>side with the grossest ignorance and the darkest
            superstition; thousands in the enjoyment of wealth for which they never laboured, and
            tens of thousands, depending for their daily bread upon the labour of their hands and
            the sensitive vibrations of the scale of commerce; political power in appearance widely
            diffused, in effect confined to the hands of a few; ignorance of the simplest elements
            of society in many of the rich and those who have power; ignorance not greater in those
            who are poor and have none—such a society, if it exists, is a society in which every
            reflecting man must at moments have misgivings as to its future condition and as to the
            happiness of those in whom he is most nearly interested. But if such a society contains
            a class, properly and truly denominated a middle class, a class neither enervated by
            excessive wealth and indolence nor depressed by poverty; a class that is characterized
            by industry and activity unexampled; a class that considers labour as the true source of
            happiness, and free inquiry on all subjects as the best privilege of a free man— such a
            society may exist and continue to be indefinitely in a state of progressive improvement
            Such a society, with its monstrous anomalies and defects, offers to a statesman of
            enlarged mind and vigorous understanding the strongest motive, while it supplies him
            with all the means, to give to the political system an impulse that shall carry it
            beyond the region of unstable equilibrium and place it at once in a state of security. </p>
                    <p>In such a society the simple enunciation by one possessed of power, that Education is a
            part of the business of the state, would be considered as the forerunner of some measure
            which should lay the foundation of that unity without which the temporary prosperity of
            the nation can never become permanent and its real happiness can never be secured.</p>
                    <p> The particular questions that the philosophic legislator has then to solve with
            respect to the education of the citizens, are—1. How are teachers to be taught, and what
            are they to be taught? 2. How is the body of teachers to be directed, superintended,
            rewarded, and punished? 3. What schools and what kinds of schools are to be established
            and encouraged for the Education of the people? 4. What are the teachers to teach in
            those schools? 5. Where is the immediate government of such schools to be placed? 6. And
            where the ultimate and supreme direction and control of such schools? The word Schools
            is here used as comprehending all places of Education.</p>
                    <p>It remains to consider those other relations of a man to the state in which we view him
            as a producer of wealth for his own enjoyment. Here the general principle is, that the
            pursuit and enjoyment of wealth must be left as free as the public interest requires;
            and this amount of freedom will not depend in any great degree on the form of
            government. To this head, that of the production of wealth, belong all the divisions of
            labour by which a man, to use a homely but expressive phrase, gets his living, or what
            in other words are called the professions, trades, and arts of a country. The only way
            in wich the state can with any advantage direct or control the exercise of any
            profession, trade, or art, is by requiring the person who undertakes to exercise it to
            have been trained or educated for the purpose. Whether this should be done in all cases,
            or in some and what cases, and to what extent, and how, are questions for a legislature
            guided by a philosopher to answer.</p>
                    <p>In all countries called civilized this has been done to a certain extent. The
            legislation of our own country offers instances of great errors committed by legislating
            where no legislation was wanted, or by legislating badly. Perhaps instances may also be
            noted in all countries where evil has arisen for want of legislation on the subject. We
            may explain by example</p>
                    <p>Perhaps it is unnecessary for a state to require that a shoemaker, or a tailor, or a
            painter, or a sculptor, should be required to go through a certain course of training
            before he exercises his art. The best shoemaker and best tailor will be sure to find
            employment, and individual shoemakers and tailors have as ample means of giving
            instruction in their craft as can be desired. It may be true or not true, that the best
            painters and sculptors will meet with most employment: but is<pb n="814"/>it unnecessary
            or is it necessary for a state to offer facilities and encouragement to those who design
            to educate themselves as painters and sculptors ? Most civilized nations have decided
            this question by doing so, and there are many reasons in favour of such a policy.</p>
                    <p>Ought the state to require the professor of law, of medicine, or of religious teaching,
            to undergo some kind of preliminary Education, and to obtain a certificate thereof?
            Nearly all civilized countries have required the lawyer and physician to go through some
            course of Education. There are strong reasons in some countries, our own for instance,
            both for and against such a requisition; but on the whole, the reasons seem to
            preponderate in favour of requiring such Education from him who designs to practise law,
            and still more from him who designs to practise the art of healing. Most civilized
            countries, perhaps all, except two (so for as we know), require all persons who profess
            the teaching of Religion to have received some Education, to be ascertained by some
            evidence. But in both the nations excepted, any person, however ignorant, may preach on
            subjects which the mass of the community believe or affect to believe to be of greater
            importance both for their present and future welfare than any other subjects. Professing
            to maintain, as we hope they always will do, the principle of religious freedom, these
            two nations have fallen into the greatest inconsistencies. They have checked the free
            expression of individual opinion by word of mouth, and fettered it in the written form,
            in the one country by the severe penalties of positive law, and the no less severe
            penalties of positive morality; and in the other by the penalties of positive morality
            carried to an excess which is destructive to the interests of the society itself.
              (<q>See Attorney General v. Pearson, 3 Merrivale, 353.</q>) But both nations allow any
            person, if he professes to be a teacher of religion, however ignorant he may be, to
            become the weekly, the daily instructor of thousands, including children, who derive and
            have derived no instruction of any kind except from this source. Such a teaching or
            preaching, if it only assumes the name and form of religious teaching, is permitted to
            inculcate principles which may be subversive of the political system; and it may and
            often does inculcate principles the tendency of which is to undermine the foundations of
            all social order; for it should never be forgotten that all religious teaching must
            include moral teaching, though moral teaching is quite distinct from religions teaching.
            And though it must be admitted that no teacher of religion recommends a bad thing as
            bad, he may recommend a bad thing as good, solely because he knows no better. We have
            endeavoured to point out an anomaly which exists in certain political institutions, and
            which can only be allowed to exist so long as it protects itself under a specious and an
            honoured but misunderstood name. For though it be admitted that such anomaly exist, it
            may be said that it cannot be remedied without interfering with the important principle
            of religious freedom. But what is religious or any other freedom? Is it the individual
            power of doing or saying what a man likes? Certainly not. It means no more than a
            freedom not inconsistent with the public welfare. Still it may be urged that this is
            precisely the kind of freedom with which no state, where the principle of religious
            freedom is admitted, can safely interfere. But this is only bringing us round again to
            the question, What is religious freedom? To say that it cannot be interfered with is to
            assume an answer to the question. Does what is called religious freedom, as the same is
            now understood, admitting it to produce much good, produce also any evil? If it does,
            can the evil be remedied? Is the free practice of any art or profession, Medicine or
            law, for instance, or the art of instructing children in general knowledge, or perfect
            freedom in teaching and expounding religious doctrines, inconsistent with the condition
            ef qualification? How the qualification is to be ascertained, and what it is to be, is
            the question; and it is a question which may be answered.</p>
                    <p>It may be asked: If a man should not be a teacher of Religion without complying with
            some previous conditions, why should he be allowed to write on Religion<pb n="814"/>without some like qualification, for he may do mischief by his writing as well as his
            oral preaching? This is true; and if it were possible, consistently with religious
            freedom, as here understood, to prevent persons from writing on Religion who have not
            had a competent Education, it would be a good thing to prevent them. So would it also be
            a good thing to prevent persons from writing on many other subjects, who know little or
            nothing about them, if it could be done consistently with letting those write who do
            understand what they are writing about. But it cannot be done; and as the free
            expression of opinion is essential to the full development of a nation's powers, both
            physical and intellectual, we must be content to take the bad with the good. Writing,
            however, is different from teaching and preaching. Oral instruction reaches thousands
            whom a book, however small or cheap, never can reach. If a man should propound doctrines
            destructive to all social organisation in a learned and extensive work, it might be most
            prudent to take no notice of him. If he should propound them in a form adapted for
            universal circulation, the case is different; and if his doctrines are such as tend to
            overthrow the political system under which he lives, it would be a gross inconsistency
            to allow them to be circulated. Still more, if he should go about preaching them, would
            it be the business of the state to quench such a firebrand by any means, however severe,
            that are required for the purpose.</p>
                    <p>In a Monarchy, such an evil is stopped by the monarch or his agents; but there is the
            danger that the interference may extend to cases when no real harm could be done by the
            circulation of the book or the preaching of the doctrine, and to cases in which good
            would follow. In a free state, no man is convicted of the offence of writing or
            teaching; what is bad without the judgment of his fellow-citizens— in <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England">England</name> by a jury; and though a jury
            is neither always wise nor always impartial, no better means have yet been discovered of
            reconciling the free expression of opinion with the restraint of opinions which cannot
            be broached without danger to the state.</p>
                    <p>The relation of Religion to the State is a question of vital importance to all nations,
            but to none is it of so great importance as to those of a Republican form, those in
            which political power is distributed among many individuals, and extends to a large part
            of the people in general, as distinguished from a privileged class.</p>
                    <p>He who views a state rightly views it as a Unity: the sovereign power, whether it is
            lodged in one or in many, is that which gives a unity to all the members of the social
            body. In the <name type="period" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Middle_Ages">middleage</name> history of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Europe">Europe</name>, we see two contending bodies
            in a state, a body Political and a body Ecclesiastical, and the consequence was anarchy.
            The states of Europe have long been Christian States, and the Christian Religion is
            inseparably blended with all European systems, and those of <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Americas">America</name>, which have arisen out of
            them. In one state in Europe, the <name type="place" key="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Papal_States">Papal State</name>, the constitution is
            Ecclesiastical, and the Political is merged in it. In some other states of Europe the
            Ecclesiastical body is now completely subjected by the Political; in others the
            Ecclesiastical body still possesses large political power. The paramount importance of
            Religion leads many persons to conclude that the Ecclesiastical Estate should have
            political power, or at least that it should have the sole power of regulating all its
            own concerns. Those who maintain this proposition must admit that a state is not a
            Unity: it is a divided body, one member of which is to some extent independent of the
            whole body; a monstrous anomaly which can only breed confusion and stop all social
            improvement.</p>
                    <p>If the state is to be One, must it be One as a Political body, or as a body Political
            and Religious? If there is only one religion in the state, and no other allowed, the
            state may be Politically and Religiously one. Such a state may be perfect in theory,
            but, in fact, its movements will not be towards improvement; but retrograde. Experience
            has shown that the free exercise of the understanding on all matters of speculation, on
            all matters of belief, on all matters that extend beyond the limits of sense, is as<pb n="816"/>necessary to the development of the understanding, as freedom from unwise
            restrictions on trade and industry is necessary to the increase of national wealth. If a
            state then allows each man to think, speak, and so write as he pleases, subject only to
            the condition that he shall not speak, write, or act, as to attempt to overthrow the
            power which gives him this freedom, the state must consistently declare, the sovereign
            body by its acts of legislation must declare, that it is neither a Religious nor an
            Anti-religious body. The state is neither Christian nor not- Christian. But it is
            objected—it has been admitted that all European nations are now Christian, and that
            Christianity is intimately blended with them. True; and for this reason,—the state need
            not occupy itself about the matter. It is admitted that Christianity has rooted itself
            in all our social systems deeper than any legislation can do. It pervades all society,
            its influence is above law. Christianity is therefore recognised by all; for as to the
            few speculative thinkers who do not recognise its truths, and as to the still larger
            number who are indifferent, they do not affect the great mass. It is a truth
            indisputable, a truth which no man in his senses can deny, that modern civilization is
            Christian; and that if all state establishments of religion were abolished, Christianity
            would exist in the minds of the great mass of a nation, and would be taught and
            propagated by zealous teachers. Nay, were a state to oppose itself to all religion, to
            persecute those who profess and those who teach it, Christianity would only flourish the
            more. For a state is directed by a comparatively small number, and this small number, if
            it opposed Christianity, would be precisely in the same position as if one man should
            attempt to control by force a million.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>