<TEI xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Xishi gangmu 西史綱目 (An Outline of Western History)</title>
                <editor>Research Project "Hidden Grammars of Transculturality - Migrations of Encyclopedic Knowledge and Power"</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Project Coordination</resp>
                    <name xml:id="BM">Barbara Mittler</name>
                    <name xml:id="MH">Madeleine Herren-Oesch</name>
                    <name xml:id="JK">Joachim Kurtz</name>
                    <name xml:id="KMW">Kaja Mueller-Wang</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Technical supervision and file administration</resp>
                    <name xml:id="JP">Jens Østergaard Petersen</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>TEI Header</resp>
                    <name xml:id="OS">Oliver Schulz</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Cluster of Excellence "Asia and Europe in a Global Context"</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Heidelberg University</pubPlace>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Karl Jaspers Centre for Advanced Transcultural Studies</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Voßstraße 2, Building 4400</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>69115 Heidelberg</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Germany</addrLine>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Xishi gangmu 西史綱目 (An Outline of Western History)</title>
                        <author>
                            <name type="person" ref="persons.xml#ZhouWeihan">Zhou Weihan 周維翰</name>
                        </author>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                                          
                        <edition>The 1st part is a reprint of the 1st edition of 1901.</edition>
                        
                    </editionStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Jingshi wenshe 經世文社</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Shanghai 上海</pubPlace>
                        <date>Guangxu 26[1903]</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                            <note>It seems that a third part was published or at least planned, as it is stated so in the preface. The book ends at 1000AD, which does not make much sense.
                            The first and the second part seems to have been printed in an interval of several months, it may be that the third part should have been printed, 
                            but could not because of the upheavals at the time or out of other reasons.</note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <settlement>Heidelberg University</settlement>
                        <repository>Library of the Institute of Chinese Studies</repository>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>  
                     <!--   <p>Size: 11.72 in (29,77 cm) * 8.25 in (20.96 cm) </p> -->
                        <p>Volumes: 35 juan</p>
                        <p>Script: Print</p>
                        <p>Illustrations: Some tables and maps in the very beginning, nothing more.</p>
                    </physDesc>
                    <msPart>
                        <altIdentifier>
                            <idno/>
                        </altIdentifier>
                        <msContents>
                            <p>Lemma-organization: The first 2 parts of the book are ordered into 35 juan. Ordered chronologically.</p>
                            <p>Table of contents: The first part deals with events up to the turn of the eras. The second part deals with events of the 1st millenium AD.</p>
                            <p>Index: none.</p>
                            <p>Contents: Historical and cultural events from different countries over the time.</p>
                        </msContents>
                        <history>
                            <p>The 1st part is a reprint of the 1st edition.</p>
                            <p>A scan of the work is available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
                        </history>
                    </msPart>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <settingDesc>
                <p>The book was at least partly compiled in Shanghai, as its said in the preface.</p></settingDesc>
            <textDesc>
                <channel mode="w">print</channel>
                <constitution type="single">The first two parts of the book comprise 35 juan. The events therein are ordered chronologically, 
                    whereby in the beginning of the column the Chinese way of counting is used and the year related to the Gregorian Calendar is given thereafter in smaller characters. 
                    The worldwide events are grouped to each year.              
                </constitution>
                <derivation type="abridgment"></derivation>
                <domain type="education"/>
                <factuality type="fact"/>
                <interaction type="none" active="singular" passive="world"></interaction>
                <preparedness type="none"/>
                <purpose type="inform" degree="high">The book should give an overview about Western history and therefore wide the horizon of its readers.</purpose>
                <purpose type="entertain" degree="low"/>
            </textDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="zh" usage="100">Chinese</language>                
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Scans available at the library of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Heidelberg University.</p>
            <p>Digitalization by Formax BPO Beijing Inc., special instructions for typing Chinese texts and encyclopedias developed by
                Wolfgang Schmidle et. al. at Max Planck Institute for the History of Science, Berlin. 
                Transformation of the digitized raw texts into TEI done by Wolfgang Schmidle. 
                TEI Header and mark-ups inserted by project members at Heidelberg University.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-08-01" who="#OS">created</change>
            <change when="2011-09-02" who="#OS">Questionnaire info added to TEI header</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="entry"/>       
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>